Check it out now
" Check it out now "
I got you stuck   off the realness
"I got you stuck off the realness "
We be the infamous  You heard ofus, official  Queensbridge murderers
" We be the infamous You heard of us, official Queensbridge murderers "
The Mobb comes equipped  for warfare
" The Mobb comes equipped for warfare "
Beware ofmy crime family  who got enough shots to share
"Beware of my crime family who got enough shots to share "
For all those  who want to profile and pose
"For all those who want to profile and pose "
Rock you in your face  Stab your brain with your nosebone
"Rock you in your face Stab your brain with your nosebone "
You all alone  in these streets, cousin
" You all alone in these streets, cousin "
Every man for theyself  in this land we be gunnin '
"Every man for theyself in this land we be gunnin' "
And keep them shook crews  runnin 'like they suppose to
"And keep them shook crews runnin'like they suppose to "
They come around  but they never come close to
" They come around but they never come close to "
I can see it inside your face  You're in the wrong place
"I can see it inside your face You're in the wrong place "
Cowards like you just get   their whole body laced up   with bullet holes and such
" Cowards like you just get their whole body laced up with bullet holes and such "
Speak the wrong words, man  and you will get touched
"Speak the wrong words, man and you will get touched "
You can put your whole army  against my team
" You can put your whole army against my team "
I guarantee it'll be your  very last time breathin '
"I guarantee it'll be your very last time breathin' "
Your simple words  just don 't move me  You're minor, we're major
" Your simple words just don't move me You're minor, we're major "
You're all up in the game  and don 't deserve to be a player
" You're all up in the game and don't deserve to be a player "
Don 't make me have  to call your name out  Your crew's feather weight
"Don't make me have to call your name out Your crew's featherweight "
My gunshots will  make you levitate
"My gunshots will make you levitate "
I'm only 19  but my mind is old
"I'm only 1 9 but my mind is old "
When the things get for real  my warm heart turns cold
" When the things get for real my warm heart turns cold "
Another n--a deceased  Another story gets told
"Another n... a deceased Another story gets told "
It ain't nothin'really  Hey, yo, son spark that Phillie
"It ain't nothin'really Hey, yo, son spark that Phillie "
So I can get my mind off  these yellowbacked n--s
"So I can get my mind off these yellowbacked n... s "
Why they still alive  I don't know, go figure
" Why they still alive I don't know, go figure "
[ Knocking ] Hold on a minute!
[敲门] 稍等一会!
I couldn't choose  a better location
"I couldn't choose a better location “
When the slugs penetrate  you feel a burning sensation
" When the slugs penetrate you feel a burning sensation "
Getting closer to God in a tight situation
" Getting closer to God in a tight situation "
Now, take these words home and think it through
"Now, take these words home and think it through "
Or the next rhyme I write might be about you
" Or the next rhyme I write might be about you "
Son they shook  'cause ain 't no such things  as halfway crooks
"Son they shook 'cause ain't no such things as halfway crooks "
[ Man ]  What the fuck!  Hold on a fucki n' minute!
- 他妈的到底怎么回事! - 他妈的 等下!
Cause there ain 't no thing as halfway crooks
" 'Cause there ain't no thing as halfway crooks "
Scared to death  And scared to look
"Scared to death And scared to look "
Livin' the life  that of diamonds and guns
"Livin'the life that of diamonds and guns "
There's numerous ways you  can choose to earn funds
" There's numerous ways you can choose to earn funds "
Some get shot, locked down  and turn nuns
"Some get shot, locked down and turn nuns "
Cowardly hearts end  straight up shook ones   Shook ones
" Cowardly hearts end straight up shook ones " "Shook ones "
Yo!! What the fuck?!
他妈的到底怎么了?
Yo! What the fuck, man! Quit playin' with your fuckin'self!
你他妈地算老几! 快给我他妈的滚出来!
Open the door! [ Toilet Flushing]
开门!
What the fuck, man! Who the fuck is you, nigga?
操你的老兄，你他妈的怎么回事?
Where the hell do you think you going?!
嘿，你他妈的往哪里走?
Going backstage! I 'm in the battle! You can't go backstage!
- 我要去后台，我在比赛 - 你不能去后台
Come on, dawg! I got a stamp on my hand! You gotta go around front!
- 嘿，老兄，我手上有会标 - 你只能到前面去
You just seen me, dawg! I just came from-- I didn't see nothin'!
- 你刚才还看见过我，老兄! 我才从... - 我什么也没看见
Man, you just fuckin' seen me! I just went to the bathroom! Whoa! What's happening?!
- 老兄，你他妈的刚才还看见过我! 我只不过去了下厕所! - 哦! 怎么啦?
This guy's got a fuckin' problem with me! Shut the fuck up!
- 这个傻B找我的麻烦! - 你他妈的给我闭嘴.
He's straight, dawg! He's straight!
他是来比赛的
He with you?! Yeah!
- 他是和你一起来地? - 对
Okay, cool, Future! But I think your boy got a attitude problem!
好吧, 进去罢, Future（人名）. 不过我觉得这小子态度有问题
You a crazy motherfucker,  you know that, trying to  fight bouncers and shit!
你真是个他妈的疯子, 什么人你都想去教训一下.
The fuckin' guy's obviously  got somethin' against me!
那个白痴就是看我不顺眼.
I go to the bathroom, come right back, he's actin' like he don't know me!
我去了一下厕所, 出来的时候,他就装不认识我.
Hold on, man! You fuckin' threw up on yourself, huh?!
行了，老兄 你他妈的又在出风头, 恩?
Come here, man!
快进来，老兄
[ Laughing ] Hey, Rabbit!
[Laughing] 嗨, Rabbit（人名）
I knowyou ready, Rabbit!
我知道你是最棒的, Rabbit.
Where you going?! He hurled on his shirt!
- 你要去哪里? - 他心情不太好.
Let's see! Yo! Get the fuck off me, Cheddar!
- 我们来看看. - 别他妈的来烦我,Cheddar（人名）.
What are you doin', man?!
老兄，你在干什么?
Come on! It's deal time, Rabbit!
Rabbit,比赛马上就要开始了.
Ourclique'llbe on the map  after you whup some ass tonight.
等今晚你大胜了那些笨蛋 我们的就能榜上有名了...
Me and Janeane just broke up!
我和Janeane(人名) 刚刚分手了.
What, again?! And I left her the car!
- 什么, 又分手了? - 我把汽车留给她
Oh, come on, Rabbit!
哦，Rabbit.
Yo, she says she's pregnant!
她说她怀孕了.
She's gonna need the car  if she's pregnant!
如果她真的怀孕， 她需要这辆车.
I'm gonna need a place to crash!
我需要找个地方 发泄一下
- You gonna stay at your mom's?! - [ Laughing ]
那你又要和你老妈住在一起?
Come on.
我说...
Yo! Can I get some fuckin' privacy here, man?!
你他妈的能不能给我留点隐私?
All right! Come on, man, come on! Why?
没问题. 别这样,别这样。
Yo, my bad, man!
都是我的错.
Look, if something's going to happen with this shit, it needs to happen now!
那么，你瞧 有些狗屁事情注定要发生 你是躲不开的
Hey, man, I feel you! I know exactly what  you're talking about!
嘿，老兄，我知道你的感受 我也知道你在说些什么.
All right, come on, man! Howyou feelin'?!
算啦,加油，老兄 你感觉怎么样?
I feel good! You feel good?!
- 感觉很好. - 你感觉很好?
Yeah! I'm ready! You sure?!
- 是的. - 你肯定? - 我准备好了
You ready, baby! I wanna seeyou rip that shit, all right?!
准备好，宝贝 让我要看到你踩碎那些狗屎，好吗?
It's time to let these motherfuckers know!
现在要给那些他妈的混蛋 一些颜色看看了
Yeah, you, baby! Three-One-Third! It's all you, baby!
3-1-3. 我知道你行，宝贝
Your lyrics are shitty  Like when I cop a squat
" 你他妈的唱的真差 就像被条子抓到 "
Who told you could fuck with the mighty Papa Doc
" 谁和你说你可以 随便操Papa Doc(组合名） "
For steppin' on his stage  I should rockyour knot
" 看你在舞台上面 我真他妈地想揍你 "
Don't get too close oryou might get shot @
" 你别离他妈的我太近 否则我就毙了你 "
Yo, nigga, call your mama and tell her come getyou @
" 不管怎么样， 你可以喊你老妈接你回去 "
And ifshe knew him she could bring your  midget pops with her
" 如果她了解我， 她就会把你和你的白痴音乐带走 "
I put a hole in your head like a. 12-gauge
" 我要在你头上开个12码的洞 "
Lookin'like Kris Kross Jiggity-jump your ass on stage
"你在台上摇摆你的死屁股 看起来就像个弱智 “
Cause I'm a grown man, son I'll slaughter you
" 因为我和你父亲一样老道 所以小子 我要杀死你 ”
Make your ma wish that her fat ass aborted you
" 真希望你妈的肥屁股 当初没有生下你 "
Whoa!A lot of hostility at the end of the 45 seconds. Let me get that mike from you.
哦.! 火药味真浓阿 多么精彩的45秒 两位老兄把麦克风给我
Open up a little bit! Let everybody see your Future! Know what I mean?!
多说几句， 大家会来决定你们的结果 知道我什么意思吗？
How y'all feelin' about Shorty Mike right here?!
大家认为我的兄弟shorty mike怎么样?
[ Booing, Yelling ] Kindo mediocare love? Just a'ight for ShortyMike?
看来人气不够足啊 就这么点声音给Shorty Mike?
What do you all think of Papa Doc, man?!
那么papa doc怎么样呢?
That's what I'm talking about! Papa Doc! [ Cheering ]
这就是我们要的! Papa Doc.!
A'ight, brother, you go to the next round!
好的, 老兄, 你进入下一轮
A 'ight, next up, next up...
好了, 下一位, 下一位...
is myman Bunny Rabbit...
接下来是我的哥们 Bunny Rabbit...
and Li'l Tic.
和 Li'I Tic(人名).
Come on, man, bring your asses to the stage. We ain't got all day.
快点老兄，抬起你的屁股到台上来 抓紧时间.
All right, all right. Enough of the fanfare.
好了, 好了 大家安静一下
Cal I it-- heads or tai ls! Heads!
- 你要哪一面.人头还是字 - 人头.
Tails! Choose! You first!
是字. 你来选 你先来唱.
- Show! - Li'l Tic, set it off! DJ!, 45 seconds! Spin that shit!
Li'I Tic, 你先来. D.J., 45秒，放音乐.
- I'm gonna murder this man @ -[Shouting]
" 我要杀了这个家伙 "
He the type to lose a fight with a dyke
"他看起来就是 连女人都打不赢得家伙 "
They don't laugh 'cause you wack
" 他们不会嘲笑你 因为你本来就是个白痴 "
They laugh 'cause you white with a mike @ [ Laughing ]
" 他们嘲笑你是因为 白人在舞台上还能拿着麦克风 "
You're a laughing stock  When will this laughin'stop
" 你这个笑柄 让这里笑声没法停
When you and Everlast  Bitch-ass, get popped
" 你这个狗娘养的， 最后只会去坐大牢 "
You a wigga that  invented rhyme for money
" 你这个秃子， 一辈子没有出息 "
Watch Li'l Tic split kick the Energizer Bunny
" 看我Li'I Tic 怎么来咬碎这只兴奋的兔子(Rabbit) "
Rip the Rabbit head off  Toss it to Hugh Hefner
" 让我把 Rabbit的头弄下来， 丢到Hugh Hefner(地名) "
Cause I don't play, boy  Now tell me who's fresher
" 虽然我不是花花公子， 但是告诉我谁的毛都没长齐 "
[ Crowd ] You are! L. T., that's right  Cock the heat and shoot ya
"L. T., 就是他了， 年轻人我发怒了，我要毙了你 "
I'll punish Rabbit Or obsolete Future
" 我要搞定Rabbit 和废了 Future"
My paws love to maul an M!C!
" 让MC来看看, 我就是爱扁你 "
Cause he faker than a psychic with caller I!D!
" 因为他比神经病院的病人还要变态 "
So that bullshit Save it for storage
" 你这个狗屎， 记下这些话吧 "
'Cause this is hip-hop You don't belong You're a tourist
" 这里是 hip-hop 我看你并不属于我们这里，你只是个游客 "
Soput your hockey sticks  and baseball bat away
"带上你的球棒和手套 给我滚出去 "
Cause this here Detroit 1 6 Mile Road is thataway
" 这里是底特律, 我看地铁站更适合你去表演 "
That away  [Future ] Whoa, whoa.
喔,喔.
Okay, okay. Forty-five seconds. Very nice.
好啦，45秒的表演非常精彩
And you did a good job, Li'l Bitch-- I mean, Li'l Tic! My bad!
你干得不错，Lil'白痴... 哦，对不起，我是说是Lil'Tic
Next up is my boy Bunny Rabbit!
接下来是我的朋友 Bunny Rabbit
[ Booing ] Hey, nigga, talk all that shit ifyou want to,
嗨，你们想说什么屁话就说吧
but I vouch for this motherfucker right here-- he's a motherfucking genius!
不过我保证他是个天才， 一个他妈的真正的天才.
Dig that shit! Forty-five seconds, Rabbit! DJ!, kick it!
开始唱吧，你有45秒，Rabbit. D.J., 开始吧.
Hey, yo!
嗨
- [ Booing ] - Come on!
加油!
- Where'd y'all find this nigga at?! - Hey, Rabbit!
你们从那里找来这个笨蛋? 嗨, Rabbit!
Come on, Rabbit! Come on, Rabbit!
加油啊，Rabbit!
Come on, Rabbit! Come on!
加油!
[ Man ] Choke! Choke! Choke! Choke! Choke! Choke!
下去! 下去! 下去!
Fuck you, motherfuckers! Fuck you!
去你妈的!
Yo,Jimmy! Hold up!
喂, Jimmy.! 等一下!
Man, don't even worry about it, dawg, a'ight?!
别担心这些，老兄 好吗?
I'll call you tomorrow! I got to go back inside, a'ight?!
我明天给你打电话，我得回去了
A'ight! Stay strong, my brother!
没事, 坚强点，老兄
- Yeah! - You'll rip 'em next time!
下次你会唱得好些
Yep! Yeah, next time!
是的，下次
Peace out, Rabbit!
走好，Rabbit!
What the fuck?! Oh, God! Oh, shit, Rabbit!
他妈的? 真见鬼.是Rabbit
You okay, baby?!
你还好吗？宝贝
Don't you thinkyou should have called or knocked first or something?!
你不觉得，你应该先打个电话 或是先敲一下门吗？
I mean-- The phone's disconnected!
我知道... 电话打不通
I know that, Rabbit!
我知道电话打不通，Rabbit
I got to get down to the phone place tomorrow and--
我不想接别人的电话直到明天...
- I been busy, you know?! - Rabbit, what the fuck areyou doing here?
- 我很忙, 你知道吗? - Rabbit, 你他妈的到这里来干什么?
How about knockin'?!
为什么不敲门?
Me and Janeane just broke up! Oh, I'm sorry, honey!
- 我和Janeane分手了. - 哦，我很难过，甜心
I thought you had a really good thing goin' with her!
我还以为你和她相处得很好
- She sleepin' with somebody else?! - No!
- 她和别人睡过觉? - 别这样.
Yo, I got to work in the morning, so--
我明天早上还要工作, 所以...
You and Future still, um, at that Little Caesars over in Warren?!
你还和future在那个小地方干活吗?
No! I'm down in New Detroit Stamping now!
不，我现在在底特律的一家工厂工作
Oh! Well, that's good! What?! [ Scoffs ]
－ 那挺好 － 你笑什么?
[ Giggling ] He got fired from a pizza place!
你被哪个卖皮萨的地方开除了.
Yo! At least I got a fuckin' job!
至少我他妈的还有个工作
Okay, stop it!
好，不要再说了
Only ex-cons and welfare moms work at that plant, man!
只有残疾佬和那些靠社会福利的人去上班的地方.
Baby, are y-you stayin' here for a while orwhat?!
宝贝，你在我这里要呆多长时间?
Just for a couple weeks!
就呆几周.
Got to save up enough to get my own place!
得先攒够钱再找地方住.
Just like Bob Zurowsky!
像个寄生虫一样
You're plannin' on still living at home, aren'tyou, Rabbit?! Okay!
你打算还住在家里是吗,Rabbit
What a bunch offuckin' losers!
简直一个废物.
- Fuckyou! -Jimmy!
操你妈的! Jimmy.!
- What's your problem, you little ingrate?! - What's your problem?!
你有病吗, 你这个忘恩负义气的东西?
Don't kick my fuckin' clothes! Don't fuckin' judge me, man!
你有病呀? 你他妈凭什么说我,王八蛋!
Why don't you grow up?! Goin' around actin' like a punk!
你为什么不能长大点? 出去做个小混混也好.
Motherfucker, what's up?! Stop!
- 操你妈的, 你想怎么样? - 别吵了!
Fuckin' punk! Stop it!
- 没用的废物! - 不要吵了!
-[Dog Barking] - Hey, Lily!
嗨, Lily.
Hey, baby! What are you still doin' up?!
嗨，宝贝 为什么你还没睡?
You woke me up, you know!
你知道吗，你把我吵醒了.
- Yeah, I'm sorry, baby! - What'd I do?!
- 是的，真是对不起，宝贝 - 我能怎么办?
Let's go back to bed! Will you sing to me?!
- 我带你去睡觉. - 好的，你能给我唱歌吗?
Yeah, of course I will! Come on!
是，当然我会 来吧
I know this girl
" 我认识这个女孩 "
Her name is Lily
" 她的名字叫Lily "
And it's past her bed
" 现在是睡觉的时间 "
T-I-M-E
" T-I-M-E "
She goes to sleep
" 她睡着了"
And she can just dream
" 但她没有做梦 "
And not have to be
" 当然也不用 "
In a stinky trailerwith me
" 和我住在一个大拖车里 "
Sowhen I feel blue
" 当我感到失落的时候 "
Don't knowwhat to do
" 不知道该做什么 "
I look atyou
" 我看着你 "
And I just say--
" 我就会说.... "
[ Blows Raspberry] [ Giggles ]
Pooh...
Good night, baby! Go to sleep!
晚安，宝贝，睡吧
Rabbit, ifyou're gonna live here, you have to get along with Greg!
Rabbit, 如果你要住在这儿 你必须要和Greg处理好关系.
He started it!
是他先挑起的.
You can't fuck this up for me, baby!
你突然出现了，你知道吗，宝贝.
You just can't! Whatever!
- 你就这么突然进来. - 随你便吧
No milk!
没有牛奶?
Yo, can I get a ride to work in the morning?!
明天早上我能搭你的便车去上班吗?
Where's your car?!
你的车呢?
I left it with Janeane!
我把它留给了Janeane.
- You're gonna let me borrowyour car?! - Nope!
- 你能把车借给我吗? - 不.
It's your birthday present! My birthday's not for two weeks!
- 算作你的生日礼物. - 我的生日还有2周才到.
I know!
我知道
But you're still  my little Rabbit, right?!
但你还是我的小Rabbit,对吗?
I need to get to sleep!
我得去睡觉了
Bunny! What up, doe?
Bunny.! 怎么了?
Heard about you and Janeane, dawg!
听说了你和Janeane的事情
- Thought you might be back home! - This ain't my home!
- 我想你会回家的 - 那不是我的家
Why you up so early?!
为什么起得这么早
Up, man?! I ain't even been to bed, dawg!
起床,老兄? 我根本没有睡
I came to talk toyou-- Yo, I don't got time to talk  right now! I'm late for work!
- 我来是想和你说点事情... - 我现在没时间谈，我要迟到了
Can you give me a ride?! My ma's got the car!
你能送我一程吗? 我妈把车开走了
Yo, don't tell nobody   I'm livin' back here, man!  All right, dawg!
- 别跟别人说我回来了. - 好，不会
What happened to you last night?!  I heard you got caught out!
昨天晚上你怎么了? 我听见你们在吵架.
People sayin' some fucked up shit!
有人在放狗屁吗
Yeah?! Yeah!
- 真的? - 真的.
Man, why you still goin' to The Shelter, dawg?!
老兄，你为什么还去那个地方?
Ain't nobody down there  but a bunch of clowns who ain't  got deals and never gonna get deals!
没有人会去那里 除拉那些永远得不到唱片合约的蠢货
You need to stay at home! You know Wink's got ya! Whatever, man!
- 你应该呆在家里. 我Winks建议你. - 随你便吧，老兄.
Look, I'm telling you, man, I'm on my way!
我告诉你 我现在要上手了.
And I'm takin' you with me! You're the franchise, baby!
我会把你带上. 你享有特权
The franchise?! Yeah!
特权吗? 是的.
I'm takin' a fuckin' bus to work, man!
我还得坐他妈的巴士去工作，老兄
Look! I was just on the horn with my man Roy Darucher!
听我说. 我正要向Roy Darucher推荐你.
That promo guy?! Yeah! Now Roy's all hooked up at 98!
是那个星探? 对. 现在Roy正在找人
So what's he need you for?!
那么，他为什么需要你?
What's he need me for?! Talent, dawg!
他为什么需要我? 我的天赋啊, 老兄.
And you know that's my specialty!
你知道那是我最擅长的
I'm the one that tipped him  on Big O and got that fat man  out offlippin' burgers!
是我把big O 推荐给了他 让那个死胖子不用再去卖汉堡
Roy liked what he heard,  split some cash out  for that nigga's demo!!!
Roy就像听说到的那样, 收集一些黑小子的录音母带...
and-- boom--just like that,  Big O got himself a deal,  and it's all because of me!
就像那样，一夜成名 Biy O 得到了一份合同都是因为我
Roy paid for Big O's demo?! Every penny!
Roy为Big O的母带付钱了? 一分都不少.
Ifthey thought Big O was hot,  wait till they get a taste  of B-Rabbit!
他们认为Big O唱得好吗, 那么让B.Rabbit出场吧.
I'm building an empire! I'm taking you with me! You're next!
我在建立一个帝国. 我在指引你，你是下一个
A'ight! I'll talk toyou later! A'ight!
好吧，我稍后和你谈.
Call me later, dawg! Okay!
记得和我联系. 好.
Feel like  Still might
"Feel like Still might "
Still write
"Still write "
Real life
"Real life "
Gonna jump on stage Kill mikes
" Gonna jump on stage Kill mikes "
Still white  Hate life
"Still white Hate life "
Brake lights  Stage fright
"Brake lights Stage fright "
Drawin'a blank, like
"Drawin'a blank, like "
U p! Down!
升起来! 降下去!
What up, Manny?! I know! You was late today, Sm ith!
－ 怎么了,Manny? － 你又迟到，老兄.
It wasn't my fault! My car wouldn't start!
我知道，那不是我的错，我的车坏了.
It ain't neveryour fault! I don't want to hear it!
你永远有借口，我不想听
I guess this probably isn't the best timing,
我想这不是时候,
but I really need some extra shifts, Manny!
不过我真的需要这份工作, Manny.
Are you shittin' me?! You just started working here-- Hey, Dutton!
- 你在和我放屁吗? 你刚刚才开始在这里工作... - 嗨, Dutton.
Is he shittin' me?! What?!
- 他是在和我放屁吗? - 什么?
You late again, Smith, and you're fired!
如果你再迟到,Smith, 你就给我滚蛋.
I'm lookin' for John Latourno!
我要找 John Latourno.
I can takeyou! I don't think so, Smith!
- 我可以带你去. - 我不这么认为, Smith.
Right this way! Thankyou!
- 这边走. - 谢谢你
Big wheels keep on turnin' Who the fuck is that?!
那他妈的是什么?
Greg Buehl!  [Carry me home to mykin]
Greg Buehl.
That dude is practically livin' with my fuckin' mom, dawg!
那个花花公子现在 和我倒霉妈妈住一起，老兄
[About the Southland]  They met at bingo!
他们可真是相配
Wait! Greg Buehl?! [ Continues ]
等等. Greg Buehl?
He went to ourschool, right?
他和我们曾在一个学校，对吗?
[ Chuckles ] [ Greg] Yeah!
是的!
I got to save up some money and get the hell out of here!
我得攒些钱，然后从这个鬼地方离开
This shit is ridiculous. [ Continues: Guitar]
那个狗屎让我感觉浑身不舒服.
Well, Jimmy moved in  with his mother
"Jimmy搬回去他妈妈家 "
Cause he ain't got no place to go
" 因为他没地方可去 "
And now I'm right back in the gutter
" 现在我又回来这鬼地方 "
With a garbage bag that's full of clothes
" 垃圾箱里堆满了破衣服 "
Bust it, bust it!  'Cause you live at home  in a trailer
去他的 " 因为你这家伙住在拖车里 "
What the hell you gonna do  Yee-haw!
" 你他妈的能怎么办 "
Cause I live at home in a trailer
" 我住在一个拖车里 "
-  Mom, I'm comin' home toyou  - Break it down!
" 妈妈，我回家来找你 " - 再来
Well, my name is Jimmy  His name's Greg Buehl
" 我名叫Jimmy，他叫Greg Buehl "
- Me, him and you  We went to the same school   - School
" 我,他和你曾在一个学校 "
This ain't cool  I'm in a rage
" 这可不酷，我要疯了 "
He's tappin' my mom  We're almost the same age
"他和我妈妈混在一起,却和我们年龄相同"
On the microphone  I drop bombs
" 在麦克风上，我放了炸弹 "
Look at this car  Thanks a lot, Mom
" 看看这辆破车，谢谢你老妈 "
Here, happy birthday, Rabbit
" 拿去！生日快乐，Rabbit "
Here's a brand-new car  You can have it
" 这有辆崭新的名牌车给你 "
A 1 928 Delta
" 一辆 1928 德耳塔 "
The shit won't even  get me to The Shelter
" 它甚至不能给我挡点风雨 "
And I can't even say  I'm from Motown
"我甚至不敢说我来自汽车之城(底特律)"
Cause I'm back in the 8-1 -0 now
" 但我还要回到这里来住 "
Cause I live at home in a trailer
" 我回来了住在拖车里 "
Mom, I'm comin' home to you
" 妈妈，我回家来找你 "
Jimmy, you know there's another  battle next week, right?!
Jimmy, Jimmy,你知道下周有个比赛，对吗?
- And I don't want to hear shit  about it! I'm signin' you up! - Man, don't!
- 我不想再听那些人放狗屁,我替你报名了. - 老兄，别那样.
- Come on! You got to battle! - Future, I'm notyou, dawg!
- 别这样. 你得去和别人比试一下. - Future, 我不是你
- Look at me! - Listen, once they hear you,
- 看着我 - 听着,只要他们听到你的歌
it won't matter  what color you are!
你是什么肤色就没有关系了.
Look, you win some of these battles,
你看,只要你赢得比赛
Three-One-Third will have  all the street credit we need,  with you and me as the anchors!
3-1-3rd 就能够得到这条街上所以得一切 我们俩在一起就更没有问题
Yo, did you hear that, uh, Wink has been talkin' to that promo guy?!
你听Wink说那个星探的事吗?
[ Chuckles ] Yeah! I heard that bullshit!
我听过那个狗屎的胡扯.
- Look, Wink is scandalous, dawg! - Could be a shot!
- 你知道，Wink不可靠. - 但是那可能是个机会.
You know I'm tryin' to get  straight with the Lord, my man up there!
你知道，我想直接和大老板接触, 我的人能够做到.
So I don't really like  bringin' too much negative  toward my positive world!
我不想给自己带来太多消极的影响
But Wink is just talkin' shit! There'll be no action,just talk--
Wink只是在瞎说 光说不练...
Sweet home Alabama
" Alabama甜蜜的家 "
You got a cigarette?!
你有烟吗?
[ Laughing ]
嘿嘿..
- The dude mentally ill?! - Car accident, man!
- 这家伙神经有毛病? - 他出车祸了.
He's supposed to get some big  settlement check soon or some shit!
他也许该做个全面的检查.
Man, will you hurry up  with that thing?!
老兄，那东西你修好了没有?
- Yo, try it now! - [ Sighs ]
你试一下，现在
[ Engine Cranking ] Give it some gas!
加点油.
That's what I'm takin' about, baby!
这就是我要说的
Come on, man, we goin' out tonight!
好样的，我们今天晚上出去
Uh! Uh! Yeah, tonigh-- Tonight?!
嗯 嗯 - 今晚？ - 是的，今晚
Look, fuck last night! Okay?! Forget it!
来吧, 去他妈的昨晚 好吗? 忘记它
What about gettin' straight with the Lord?!
不如我们去和大老板接触?
Come on, man, it's Saturday! I can get straight with the Lord on Sunday!
我说老兄，今天是星期六 我可以直接和大老板在星期天谈
[Hip-hop ] Oh, hey, ""B", I got these new beats, man!
哦, 嗨, "B",我刚刚搞到这些新曲子
You know how much i like  your moms and everything, "B'"--
你知道我有多喜欢你妈和她的一切，B...
Shit! How much I really, really like your mama, Rabbit! [ Laughs ]
去他妈的. 我是真的真的喜欢你妈啊, Rabbit.
But she wasn't doin'you no favor  when she left you this car, man.
不过她真的留了部好车给你啊,老兄
Fuckyou! Get out and walk! At least the radio plays!
- 操你妈的. 滚出走路吧 - 至少有收音机听
[Rap ] What up with the whole  East CoastlWest Coast thing?!
这些东海岸和西海岸唱的东西怎么样，老兄?
Word! We got to put the Mo on the map.
- 像在读单词 －就像在麦克上呻吟
Yeah! Talk about the 3-1 -3!
就是. 让我们谈谈 3-1 -3.
Man, nobody even knows Detroit is in 3-1 -3!
老兄, 没有人知道底特律会有 3-1 -3.
Three-one-three! Three-one-three!
3-1-3!
What the fuck you talkin' about?! You from 8-1 -0!
他妈的你们在谈什么? 你是从 8英里街来的.
Man, we just got to make our own sound! Fuck everybody else!
我们要做我们自己的音乐. 让别人他妈的说去吧.
Then we get us a deal, go platinum,
到时候我们更得到合约, 让他们瞧瞧,
get cheesedout...
让恶心的人滚蛋...
and get all the bitches!
然后搞定所有的婊子
- All the ho's! - Mmm!
- 所以人的目光. - 嗯!
Doyou think  I have a big head?!
你们认为我怎样?
- [ Clears Throat ] - Ohh! Ohh!
- 哦! 喔!
- Oh, shit! - Why'dyou bring that  damn thing, man?
- 哦, 狗屎! - 你怎么把那个该死的带来了?
- Oh, man. Do it! - Shoot!Shoot!
- 哦，伙计，帅呆啦! - 射吧射!
- Pinkeye, bitch! - Let me see! Let me see! Let me see! Let me see!
- 红眼的婊子! - 让我来! 让我来!
Let me show you motherfuckers  how to shoot something!  Let me show you!
我来给你们这些杂种表演什么叫射击
- Do it, do it, do it! - [ Horn Honking ]
射 射 射
Oh, okay, okay! Here we go! Here we go!
好了，过去，过去
Here it is! Here it is! Here it is!
来了 来了
Take the wheel, man! Come on,Jimmy! Come on, man!
你帮我开车.
Take the gas! You got the gas! Man, come on, Rabbit.
加油, Rabbit.
[D.J. Iz] Hey, Rabbit, get back in the car, man.
嗨, Rabbit, 进到车里面来啊.
Hit the bus! Hit the bus! Hit the bus!
射那个巴士，射那个巴士!
- Ooh! - Oh, no! - No! Don't do that!
- 哦! - 哦, 不! - 不要! 不要那么做!
Oh, shit, man!
哦，妈的!
What the fuck is wrong with you?! [ Laughing ]
你他妈脑子坏了?
- Oh, shit! - Fuck!
- 哦,妈的! - 操!
Toss the weed! Toss the weed, Cheddar!
把烟熄了，Cheddar!
- Toss the motherfuckin' weed! - Throw it out!
- 快把她妈的烟熄了! - 丢了它!
-[Music, Engine Stops ] - What the fuckyou doin'?!
- 你他妈干什么?
- The fuckin' carjust died, dawg! - Oh, come on, man!
- 这倒霉车熄火了. - 哦,不要
I told you stupid-ass niggas  not to be doin' that shit!
我告诉过你们这些笨蛋不要做那种蠢事
That rifle ain't mine, right,Jimmy?! I don't want to go to jail!
那支枪不是我的,对吗Jimmy? 我不想蹲监狱
Shut the fuck up, Cheddar! I'm fuckin' serious! I get claustrophobic!
- 闭上你得丑嘴, Cheddar. - 我他妈的是认真得. 我有幽闭恐怖症.
You were scared! You were scared!
你害怕了，你害怕了
No, you were scared! You were scared!
不是,你才害怕呢
Man, you know how many  abandoned buildings  we have in Detroit?!
你们知道在底特律有多少被遗弃的房子?
How are you supposed to  take pride in your neighborhood  with shit like that next door?!
难道我们能为我们的那些狗屎邻居感到骄傲?
And does the city tear 'em down?!
城市堕落了吗?
No! They too busy  building casinos and taking   money from the people!
不，他们忙着建赌场和妓院，把人们的钱全赚走
Shut your preachin' ass up! Nobody care about that shit!
少在那里放屁了 没有人会去关心这些垃圾
Did you care when  that crackhead raped   that little girl?!
你难道不知道有人在里面强奸了个小女孩吗?
You think that would have happened  if he didn't have an abandoned house to take her to?!
如果没有这些破房子 那人会有机会做这鬼事?
They caught him, didn't they?! Yeah, they caught him.
- 警察抓住他了? - 是的, 他被抓了.
Dumb mother fucker  went back to the house!
那个傻B又回到那所房子.
How stupid  could a nigga be?!
他真是傻透了
Yo, Rabbit! What's happening  under that hood, man?! It's just a short! Chill out!
- Rabbit. 车到底怎么了? - 只是有点短路,稍等
I ain't gettin' back in  that piece of shit! It's a deathtrap!
我才不要坐回那个狗屎， 简直是个炸弹
I think Jimmy's mom's tryin'to killhim.
我想Jimmy的老妈是想害死他
Yeah! But she's so god damn fine! Hell, yes!
不过他老妈真是正点 该死的，是啊
Don't be sayin' shit about my mom or my fuckin' car, man!
不要在那里说我妈和这倒霉车的坏话
I hear everythin'!
我什么都能听见
- He a ninja now?! - [ Engine Starts ]
他是千里耳?
Hey, Rabbit! Okay, okay, okay.
嗨, Rabbit! 好了, 好了
It's about time.  Money underthe hood.  Money on the mike
时间不早了.
Freaky gals  here we come  Yo! Let me get a light, DJ!!
让我把灯打开, D.J...
I gotta get mine  You gotta getyours
[Rap]"I gotta get mine You gotta get yours "
I gotta get mine You gotta getyours
You gotta get yours
[ Future ] A w, shit. What the fuck's goin'on out here?
哦，见鬼，这里发生了什么?
What's up, man?! You all right?! Yeah, I 'm cool!
- 老兄，你还好吧? - 是的, 我很好.
Yeah?! You sure?! Yeah!
你确定? 是
You the man, Rabbit! Yeah!
你是最好的, Rabbit. 对.
I use myvoice to speak the fiery frame, try and refrain
[Rap]" 我用我火热的声音一遍遍地唱"
Come on, baby, it's redemption time! Come on, man! Come on, man!
来吧，宝贝，该你出场了. 来吧
I be the nigga in The Shelter I aim to change
" 我躲在自己的世界里寻求改变 "
Three-one-three area  Bomb and buryyou  with vengeance
" 3-1-3就要把你炸平和埋葬"
My rhyme sentences will put an end to your existence
" 让我的音乐来给你做个了解 "
With a rigorousness  Niggas, I'm serious
" 你这个残酷的吝啬鬼 "
Delirious  Cause a curious
"迷乱带来我的疯狂 "
Pause the fury calls  Through my jaws from  devouring y'all raw
" 只有生吞下你们我才能停止愤怒 "
Whoo! Okay, okay. Three-One-Third, we in the house.
呜! 好了,好了,3-1-3 我们来了.
You know what I mean. Mac Mitten's finest. D.J., give me that beat.
我知道Mac Mitten你是最棒的. DJ，给我个节奏
- [ Iz Imitating Beat Box ] - Come on. Come on. Uh, uh, uh, uh.
来吧,来. 嗯, 嗯
You forced to I isten to the i ndividual, the metaphysical
" 你们被迫听我个人的胡说八道 "
The Mac Mitten rhyme ritual  Heterosexual
" Mac Mitten的旋律听起来真爽 "
Syllables, they sound  complex to you
" 一个个音节，听起来是那么复杂 "
Line's perplexin' you . With words that could put a hex on you
" 每一句使你听起来像是着了魔"
Snap that neck on you  Murder you, boil you
" 勒死你，谋杀你，煮熟你 "
We keep a white boy or two  Let my man grab the mike
"让我得白人小子来刺激你们一下 "
You'll see how Bunny Rabbit do   Come on, man.
" 你会看到 Bunny Rabbit 有多棒 "
Come on, man! Come on! Kick that shit, baby! Come on!
快点，老兄 给他们点颜色看看, 宝贝.
Come on, man.
快点
- Uh, uh! - Watch that nigga kick this shit!
- 嗯,嗯. - 给他点颜色看.
- All right, speed it up a little bit, Iz! - Come on, baby!
- 好吧, 节奏快一点, Iz. - 加油
All right, look! Yo! Yo!
好的 呦.呦
Your style is generic Mine's authentic made
" 你的风格太一般，我得才叫酷 "
I roll like a renegade You need clinic aid
" 我得表演才叫够另类， 你更需要的是去看医生 "
My techniques bizarre and ill. I scar and kill
" 我得水平奇异又够狠， 能吓死你杀了你 "
You were a star until I served you like a bar and grill
" 直到我蹂躏你前你还勉强算个歌手 "
As I proceed to cook  and grill ya, that's   all it took to killya
" 在我拷问你的时候我随便就能搞定你 "
You better recognize me  Like I look familiar
" 你们最好记得我承认我 "
You wanna battle?  You beat around the bush   like you scared to lick pussy
" 你想和我比赛 你只会害怕的去舔女人的阴户 "
So you eat around the tush. I need a clown to push
"  虽然你像个到处觅食的小狗， 但是我还是需要个白痴对手 "
Someone that I can bully. Wait a minute, I don't think  you understand fully
" 我就是恐吓你， 等一下好像你还不太明白我都话 "
Me without a style is like  mustard without the Heinz  i lead the new school
" 我得风格就是我的命根， 我们是新潮流的开创者 "
You're a buster without the rhymes, I'll crush  the shit outya lines
" 你们只是会乱叫的野兽， 我要把你们这些狗屎都捻碎 "
Now I'm Da Sheki  Smokin' da leaky leaky
" 现在我是Da Sheki 只会天天抽烟人"
Ten freaky girls   inside the Chin Tiki
"  Chin Tiki里有很多捉摸不定的女孩 "
- Girl, when you see me  - You better believe me
- " 女孩，当你看到我得时候 " - " 你最好相信我 "
This ain't a game  And pimpin' ain't easy
" 这不是游戏 " " 玩起来也不简单 "
Anything goes  when it come to ho's
"任何事情都会发生， 只要时间到了 "
I'm the king in  when it comes to flows @
"当时机到了的时候 我就是一切的主宰 "
You better ask someone  if you don't know
" 你最好问问别人， 如果你不知道的话 "
- When you see me girl say  - What up, doe
" 当女孩看到我时都会说 " " 你好吗，宝贝 "
Chin Tiki girls  Chin Chin Chin Tiki girls
" Chin Tiki 女孩 " Chin Chin Chin Tiki 女孩 "
- Oh, shit! Look, man! -[ Chattering Stops ]
见鬼，看看谁来了
Listen up now! Leadaz of Tha Free World in the motherfuckin' house!
听好了， 现在free world 的领袖来到这个鬼地方
- Me and Papa Doc will battle  any motherfuckers here! - Yeah!
- 我和 Papa Doc 比这里任何人都要强. - 对.
- Told you them niggas  was talkin' shit! - Man, fuck The Free World!
- 我看他又在放屁 - 喂, 操freeworld
- Yeah! Fuck Tha Free World! [ Chuckles ] - Fuck Tha Free World?!
- 操freeworld! - 操freeworld?
You Three-One-Third bitches  is wack.
你们313的就像是婊子养的怪胎
Hey, yo, fat ass  Yeah, I'm talking about your man Sol
" 嗨，死胖子 对, 就是说你呢 Sol "
I bet if I kicked you  in your chest, pork chops  will fall out your asshole
" 我打赌如果我踢你的胸， 你的屁眼里面就能出猪排 "
You cats is pussy  soft like wet flowers
" 你们简直就像脓包一样 "
Leadaz of Tha Free World here to smash all you cowards
" Free World就是来打碎你们这些懦夫的 "
- Look at Future--  - Don't even start, nigga!
- " 看看Future..." - 你最好别乱说，白痴
- What you gonna do about it, faggot?! - Who you callin' a faggot?!
- 你有能怎么样, 蠢货? - 你为什么叫我蠢货?
Don't play yourself, bitch!
你连自慰都不会，王八蛋?
Holdon. Yo, Elvis. You don't wanna step to this.
等等, Elvis. 你不会想要这样吧.
You need to take that  white-ass rap shit of yours  back across 8 Mile!
你只要把你的那位白人混小子带回8英里街
Caught your choke act   at. The Shelterlast night.
那个昨天晚上一声不出的哑巴
- Oh, shit! - [ Yelling ]
- 哦,操你妈!
Hey, what you gonna do about this, niggas?!
嘿,你们想怎么样 尝尝这个怎么样,蠢货?
- Come on, man! - No, no, no! Put the shit down!
- 来啊. - 不不，快把那个狗屁东西收起来
- Come on, now! - Pull out! Pull out!
把他们拉开,拉开!
- Chill, man. Come on, man. - Yo, yo! It's cool!
- 冷静，老兄 - 行了，住手
Come on, now! It's cool.
行了，冷静点
- Yo, come on, man, let's go! - Come on!
行了，我们走
I should fuckyou up, Cheddar!
我真应该扁你一顿,Cheddar.
What the fuck were you thinkin', man?! ""FuckTha Free World!"
你他的地到底怎么想的? 操freeworld
You just said it! @@ [Hip-Hop ]
就像你说的一样.
Yeah, Hip-Hop Shop! Leadaz of.Tha Free World! A'ight, dawg!
喂, Hip-Hop商店. The Free World最好的.
Hey, Hip-Hop Shop, Wednesday night!
Hey, Hip-Hop 商店, 星期三晚上.
Come on down. Come on down.
来吧.
Hey, girl, uh, it's gonna be your only opportunityto blow the both ofus, baby.
嗨，小妞这是你唯一见到我们的机会
'Cause after we go platinum, you won't be able to get to me and Future!
因为等我们出名以后你不可能看到我和Future
And, uh, why do  they call you Future?!
为什么大家叫你Future?
See, I had a lot of names, you know, the most conceited kind!
你知道，我有很多名字,都很不错
I was, uh, Maximum Brimstone, Godfather "D'", Devastatin' "D'",
有 极限硫黄, 教父 "D", 毁灭者 "D",
Big "" D" -- you know, that has a double meaning to it!
大头 "D"...你知道, 这个有双重含义...
But see, none ofthose really worked for me...
不过，我都不是很喜欢
till I started hosting those battles  down at The Shelter.
直到我开始在会所里面开始主持比赛
One day, somebody said, "You know what, man?
有一天，一个老兄对我说:"你知道吗!"
You are the future  of hip-hop in Detroit!"
你是整个底特律 Hip-Hop的未来
So you see, baby, sometimes you got to find your name and, uh,
所以，宝贝有时候你要费心取个名字，嗯
other times, your name finds you.
有时候，你的名字会来找你
You want to  smoke some ganja?!
你要些大麻吗?
See, that's our problem.  If we don't respect  our sisters, who will?
看，这就是我们的毛病， 如果我们不尊重我们的姐妹，那还有谁会?
Yo, we're doin' it  to ourselves!
我们必须从自己做起
He's my brother! He don't like pussy!
他是我兄弟 他不喜欢阴道.
Yo, Rabbit. Teach me to write rhymes.
喂, Rabbit. 告诉我怎么唱那些歌.
That's the way to get the ladies, right?!
那是个泡妞的好方法不是吗?
Let me out!
让我出去
Yo, yo, hold up! Look, I'm sorry!
等会 老兄你看, 真是对不起.
I didn't know Papa and L!C! were on their bullshit until tonight!
直到那天晚上我才知道 Papa和L.C是狗娘养的
Look, man, you know I wouldn't be messin' with them!!!
老兄,我不能没有他们...
except I'm promotin' a show with them at the Hip-Hop Shop next week!
直到完成下个星期的Hip-Hop商店的秀
Those Free World bitches?!
freeworld的那3个王八蛋吗?
You see that the fuck i'm talkin' about,Jimmy?!
你看见我说得那些混蛋了吗,Jimmy?
Look, man, they're just one of the acts!
别这样，他们只是表演的一部分
Hey, Jimmy, if you want, I'll step out, man! You're my friend!
嗨,如果你一定要那样，我就退出， 你还是我的朋友
I don't want you  bein' mad at me! Man, do what you want to do!
我不想你为我难堪. 老兄，你想怎么做就怎么做
Yeah, do what you want to do, dawg!
是的, 想怎么做就怎么做
Only respect, baby! Let's go!
只是聊聊，宝贝 我们走吧
Respect yourself, sister!
你要小心,姐妹.
Hey, don't you  ever shut up, man?!
嗨,你就不能闭嘴吗?
Why you got to push me?!  Damn, Future!
你为什么推我? 去你的, Future.
Man, what the hell  is his problem?!
他到底有什么毛病?
Future?! Yeah!
Future? 是的
- Thinks sometimes  you talk some bullshit!  - Who is he to saywhat's real?!
- 他认为你有时尽说废话 - 他为什么总是把什么事都当真?
Just 'cause he hosts  those battles?!
就因为他是比赛的主持吗?
Ain't that Janeane  over there?!
那不是Janeane在那边吗?
- Oh, yeah!  - I thoughtshe was pregnant.
- 是的. - 我想她是怀孕了.
- I'm out, dawg! I'll be outside! - Yeah!
- 让我出去,老兄. 我到外面去. - 好的
A'ight! A'ight, man!
再见，老兄
By myself!
单独一个人.
I'm gonna ask him! Well, here's your chance, girl! Go ahead!
我要过去一下.
You're Jimmy Smith,Jr! Yeah!
你是Jimmy Smith, Jr对吗? - 是的
My name's Alex!
我叫 Alex.
So did you find the guy  you was lookin' for?!
你找到你要找的人了吗?
What guy?! The friend!
什么人? 你的朋友.
Yeah! That was my brother! I was borrowing a car!
对. 他是我哥哥. 我去借部车.
So!!! I hear you're  a real dope rapper!
嗯... 我听说你是个很出色的Rap歌手.
A dope rapper?! Yeah!
- 出色的Rap歌手? - 对.
Who told you I was a dope rapper?!
谁告诉你的?
You know, it's around!
你知道，大家都那么说.
If you're so dope,  what you doin' workin' over  at Dead End Stampin'?!
如果你真的那么出色， 为什么还在没有前途的工厂工作?
Your brother works there!  Yeah, my brother's a loser!
你哥哥也在那里工作. 是的, 我哥是个失败者.
What about you?!
那么说说你吧?
I'm workin' at Intermezzo, savin' up enough cash to get out ofthis place!
我在剧团工作 赚够钱，然后离开这个鬼地方.
Well, busin' dishes is much better than pressin' bumpers!
洗盘子也比在工厂干体力活要好呀
I'm not gonna be there long!
我不会在这里呆很长时间
Where are you goin'?!  New York!
你要去哪里? 纽约
I won this modeling contest a couple of months ago!
我几个月前参加一个模特比赛
One of the judges said  he could help me out!
有个评委说可以他可以帮我出道
Just got to get a book together! What ifhe ain't for real?!
- 只是随便谈谈罢了 - 也许他是随便说说?
All I'm lookin' for is a ticket!
我在这儿就想搞张车票
Yo, Rabbit. You and your  new friend want to bounce  to an after-hours spot?
嗨, Rabbit.你和你的新朋友跟我们一起吗?
Rabbit?!
Rabbit?
Let me go ask my friends!
让我去问问我得朋友.
So where we goin'?! Hmm?! Oh! My house!
那我们接下来去哪里? 哦，去我家.
What about your mom?! Workin' nights now!
你妈不是在家吗? 上夜班去了.
This the after-hours spot?! Heck, yeah!
这就是那个找乐子的地方? 嘿,是的.
Can some of us ride with you?!
我能和你们一起去吗?
- Why do they call you Rabbit?! - He's fast and he likes to fuck!
- 为什么大家叫你Rabbit? - 他跑得快又喜欢操
- Oh, well! - Get your hand off my balls!
把你手拿开!
- Man, why doyou be all ignorant for?! - Oh, shit! Jimmy!
- 老兄,你怎么这么无知? - 哦，Jimmy，小心点
- What's the matterwith you?! - My bad, you guys!
- 你到底怎么回事? - 我知道该怎么办，小子们.
Soyou signed anything yet?! Notyet, but but I'm workin' on a little somethin' somethin'!
- 你已经签约了吗? - 他还没有签约
- Yeah?! - Yeah. He's gonna be courtin' a demo at MCA soon.
- 什么? - 我正在帮他给MCA录制母带
- Really?! - Yeah, well--
- 真的? - 是的，但是...
If you really  want to see Jimmy flow,
如果你真的要了解Jimmy
make sure you come down   to the next battle at The Shelter!
记得下次来看他在会所得比赛
Yeah! He's the best!
是的是的，他是最好的!
- Shut up, Cheddar! - When's the battle?! - Friday night!
- 闭嘴, Cheddar. - 什么时候比赛? - 星期五的晚上.
Yeah?! Can I come?!
是吗? 我能来吗?
There's no way I'm fuckin' battlin' next Friday, dawg!
我下周五不会去他妈的比赛
You know damn well  you're gonna battle if she's there!
我知道你会去的，因为她会在那
'Causeyou're gonna  want to be the man,  you know what I'm sayin'?
你要像个男人，你知道我在说什么吗?
All right, man!  J ust don't fuckin' push!  Guess we all need to be pushed!
- 嗨，老兄你别老逼我. - 有的时候，就得有人来逼你
Ha! My bad! I'm sorry! [ Laughing ]
哈，我的老兄，真是对不起
You gonna let him push you?! You could never catch me and you neverwill!
- 你他妈来真的? - 你永远也抓不到我!
Out of myway, freaky girl! [ Laughing ]
别挡路 小妞!
Wipeyour feet!
小心!
You like?! Hmm?!
你喜欢她?
She's getting out ofthe ""D," though! Hey, bro, please!
尽管她要离开底特律 - 嗨，老兄.
That's what they all say!
她不是那么好对付的.
Nah! I think she's different!
我认为她与众不同.
Hey, man, that chick really blew both you guys?!
嗨，老兄，那个鸡真的和你们两个都干吗?
I'm a sinner,James!
我是个罪人, James.
Come to the church with me in the morning, a'ight?
明天早上和我一起去教堂,好吗?
Hey!
嗨
Uh, I saw you talkin' to Papa Doc in Chin Tiki!
我在Chin Tiki看到过你和Papa Doc谈话
How you know him?! You mean Clarence?!
- 你怎么认识他? - 你是说Clarence?
He went to Cranbrook  with Christine's brother!
他和Christine的哥哥一起来玩过.
Doyou want to dance? Not right now.
- 你想跳舞吗? - 现在不想
Fuckin' Wink, man!
操他的Wink
Tryin' to keep us in division  with all that fake-ass,  Big Willie wannabe talk!
他不想我们和那些混蛋一起, 和他们谈的时候你可得小心点.
Shit wrong with a free demo! Free comes with a dick right upyour ass,Jimmy!
都是能够免费录制母带惹得祸. 免费只会在那些人操你的屁股以后, Jimmy.
Three-One-Third is real!  The shit thatWink  is talkin' about is wack!
3-1-3从不信那个狗屎说的鬼话
I don't understand  whythe media's not  all overthis!
我不知道媒体为什么不关心这件事
It's just a matter oftime before it all happens again! The city don't give a fuck!
再次发生只是时间的问题 但是根本就没人他妈的理我
[Together]  What the hell  is he talkin' about?!
你他妈的说什么呢?
That abandoned house where  that little girl got raped!
那所被遗弃的房子就是强奸那个女孩的地方
[D.J. Iz] Whatyou call "an attractive nuisance. '"
[DJ. Iz] 你们说得"诱惑之地"
You better believe that place  wouldn't still be standing if it  was on the other side of 8 Mile!
你最好相信我说得， 如果那房子在8英里街之外早就会给拆了
It could have been Lily, Rabbit!
下一个可能是Lily呀，Rabbit
Burn this shit down to the ground! Burn it down!
把这些狗屎全都烧了 全烧光，全烧光
- That's what I'm talkin' about! - Okay, I got it!
- 这就是我说的. - 好了.
Fuckin' yeah, man! Let's burn this fuckin' thing down!
操他的. 让我们烧掉这狗屎.
- Let's go, Cheddar.  - This is the definition  of an attractive nuisance.
- 快出去, Cheddar. - 这就是它的末日.
- Hey, Rock! Come on, Rock. Let's burn this thing. - Right behindyou, man.
- 嗨, Rock.! 要烧了. - 就来了
- That's what I'm talkin 'about. - Yeah, baby.
这就是我要做的
Could have sworn  I had some matches.  You got some?
我得火柴呢. 你有火吗?
You got my I i ghter?! I gave it back to you!
你拿了我打火机吗? 我刚才还给你了.
- I got one! - Wink, you got the lighter?
- 我有一个. - Wink, 你有打火机吗?
[ All ] No!
不!
- Oh, shit! Get out! - Run!
- 哦，妈的，快出去! - 出去!
Hey, what the fuck, you guys?!
这他妈是干什么，你们这帮家伙?
I'm out! Fuckyou, Cheddar!
我出来了! 操你妈的, Cheddar!
Hey, Rabbit, word!
嗨, Rabbit, 过来!
Rah! Hey, I burned   the house down! [ Laughing ]
嗨，我把这房子给点着了
The roof The roof
" 房顶 房顶 "
The roofis on fire We don't need no water
" 房子着火了， 我们需要水 "
Let the motherfucker burn  Burn, motherfucker
" 让它他妈的烧吧 烧吧, 傻B，烧吧 "
Burn  It's almost beautiful!
"烧吧 - 这看起来真漂亮.
When I was little, I used to want to live in a house like this!
你知道，我从小就想在这样的房子里住
You know, how it used to be!
曾经是吧
You live with your family?! [Siren Blaring, Distant]
你和你家里人一起住吗?
I got out of there  as quick as I could!
我可不想和他们在一起多呆一分钟
Left home when I was 1 7! What about you?!
我17岁时我就离开家了 你呢？
Sort of the same! [ Cheering, Shouting]
差不多吧
When you record a demo,
当你录制你的母带的时候
I'd really love to be there!
我也非常想参加
Alex! Hey, girl!
Alex
You're gonna be great! [Siren Blaring]
你会成名的
I got a feelin' about ya! [Woman ] Let's go, Alex.
我有这种预感 - 我们走吧, Alex.
See ya! See ya!
再见.
[Future ] Cheddar, bring your ass on! Come on!
Cheddar, 你他妈的在那干什么呢!
Shit! What's the matter?!
- 见鬼! - 怎么回事?
We're bein' evicted! Goddamn it!
我们的房租到期了 操他妈的!
Come on, Mom! Not in front of Lily!
别着急，妈 lily还在那呢
I can't let Greg  find out about this!
我不能让Greg知道这个
Fuck Greg!
操 Greg.
Okay! I'm three months late!
好吧. 3个月了
We got 30 days  to come up with the money!  What doyou mean ""we"?!
- 那么，我们还有30天去弄钱 - 你说"我们"是什么意思?
Ifyou're gonna live here, you got to start chippin' in, Rabbit!
如果你还想住在这里 你就得拿一部分钱,Rabbit.
When's Greggettin' his settlement check?  Get the money from him.
为什么不让Greg来付账? 从他那里要钱
No, no, I can't!
不，不，我不能那么做
He's gonna ask me and Lily  to move away with him!
他会离开我和Lily
Someplace nice, real soon!
我得赶快想办法
I-I can't freak him out.  You got to stop  livin' your life like this!
- 我...我不能告诉他. - 你不能再这样的生活下去
Ifyou really cared about Lily,  you would get ajob  and quit fuckin'around.
如果你真的在乎Lily， 你得去找个工作，然后离开这个鬼地方
I got to go! Be late for work!
我得走了. 要不上班又要迟到.
What are you doin' with your life that's so great, Rabbit?!
那么你觉得你的生活很棒吗,Rabbit?
Wink's workin' on a deal where I can get free studio time!!!
Wink和他们商量过,我很快就有免费的录音.
to record my demo!
录制我的母带
Yeah! Right!
哦，挺好
Bye, baby!
再见，宝贝
Alex Latourno Hotter than an inferno
" Alex Latourno 比地狱还火热 "
Up! @ Hotter than a crack house
升! " 比燃烧的房子还火辣 "
- Down! - @ Burn internal @
-降! - " 内心在燃烧 "
Up! Down!
升! 降!
I don't know why Manny's got to give me so much shit all the time, man!
我不知道为什么Manny总是给我脸色看
Maybe it's 'causeyou keep giving him reason to!
可能是你总是给他借口
Stick to the plan, man!
按时完成生产计划，孩子
Just do your work  and shut the fuck up!
好好的做事，少发牢骚
Up!
升!
Down!
降!
Why haven't you called?!
你为什么不打电话给我?
Janeane, I can't  talk about this here!  You're gonna get me fired!
Janeane, 我现在不能和你谈这个. 你会让我被开除的.
I'm your girlfriend!  No, you're  not my girlfriend!
- 我是你女朋友 - 不，你不是我的女朋友
We broke up! I'll call you later!
我们分手了 我过会给你打电话
You just took off  without sayin' a word!
你不能什么都不说就这么走了
At least I left you the car!  Was it 'cause I said  I was pregnant?!
至少我把车给你留下了. - 就因为我说我怀孕了吗?
Come on,Janeane!  I know why you said that bullshit!
别这样, Janeane. 我知道你为什么那么胡说
You got to get out ofhere! I didn't know what else to do!
- 你赶快走吧 - 但是我不知道还能做什么
Tell me whyyou left  and I'll leaveyou alone!  It's notyou, okay?!
- 告诉我你为什么离开, 我就走 - 不是你的原因行吗?
Janeane, it's me! It's my shit! I had to go!
Janeane, 是我. 都是我得错. 我要走
Why?! What areyou running from?!
为什么? 你在逃避什么?
Nothing! Would you just go?!
什么都不是 你能不能赶快给我走?
You know that everybody's calling you a loser  from the other night?!
你知道吗，从那天晚上起 大家就都说你是个失败者?
- Who said that?! - Everybody's talking about it!
- 谁说的? - 所有的人都在谈论这件事.
How you froze up  and got booed offstage!
说你怎么在台上一动不动， 然后被嘘下台
- Fuckyou,Janeane! Go home! - [ Chuckling ]
操你Janeane，赶快回家吧
- What was all that about?! - I'm sorry, Manny! It wasn't my--
- 那到底是这么回事? - 对不起, Manny. 那不是我得...
- It won't happen again! - Good!
- 不会再发生了. - 很好.
Don't be bringin' that shit around here!
你不应该把那些狗屁带到这来
Nowget back to work.
现在赶快回去工作
Rakim was the first rapper  to get complex lyrics, man.  I give you Rakim, no question!
Rakim 是第一个能唱复杂旋律的rap歌手， 我推荐他，绝对没错
But as far as beat and lyrics  go, Biggie is the bomb!  I don't believe this shit!
不过从节奏上面， Biggie 才是最好的 - 我才不信你说的狗屎
Y'all gonna talk about complex shit and then leave out my man Tupac!
你们在谈复杂节奏的时候 却不提我的偶像 Tupac
FuckTupac!  FuckTupac?! Nigga, you crazy!
- 操 Tupac! - 操 Tupac? 你是不是疯了!
- Pac's the only lyrical  motherfucker out there!  - His shit do got emotion!
- Pac's是这里最他妈有活力的. - 他是有点水平.
What about the Beasties?! [Future ] Man, fuck the Beasties.
- Beasties怎么样? [Future] 操 Beasties.
How you even gonna bring the Beasties' shit in the mix?!
你怎么会想到Beasties?
They bust  some serious shit!
他们的造型还不错
No! The white boys, that's more like busters on some serious shit!
那些白人小子，造型就像白痴
I ain't gonna be bumpin' no Beastie,
我不是中伤 Beastie
but it's always easier for  a white man to succeed in  a black man's medium, right?!
不过白人唱黑人的歌总是比较容易成功,对吗?
[Future ] Wordup. That's true.
一语中的.说得好
Yo! Whoa!
哦
- Hey, hey, hey, hey! -All right.
- 嗨, 嗨! - 怎么了.
What you doin', man?! Rabbit!
你要干什么? Rabbit!
- Oh, shit! - Don't you worry, Rabbit! I got your back!
- 哦, 妈的! - 不要担心, Rabbit. 我在后面支援.
Hey! Hey, what's up, ""B"?!
嗨嗨，怎么了,"B"?
- You wanna fuck with us, bitch?! - Shut your bitch-ass up!
- 你想操我们是吗,婊子? - 闭上你的臭嘴
- [ Yelling ] - Get off my man!
放开他!
Yo, get offme, man!
放开我!
Yeah! You wanna  fuck with us?! Huh?!
你想操我们是吗，嗯?
- Fuckwith us, yeah?! - Cheddar, what the fuck areyou doin'?!
- 来操我们啊? - Cheddar,你在他妈的干什么呢?
- Where did you get that shit?! - It's my mom's!
- 你从哪里搞到的这个东西? - 从我妈妈那里拿的.
Man, put that shit away, dawg, beforeyou fuckin' kill somebody!
赶快把那东西收起来 你他妈的会杀死人的!
- Papa Doc had one! - Put it away!
- Papa Doc 也有! - 把它收起来!
- Man, put that down, man! - Come on, Cheddar.
- 我说你把那东西放下 - 别这样, Cheddar.
- Okay! All right! - [ Gunshot] - Fuck man!
- 好吧 - 操他的!
- Oh, shit! - What the fuck?!
- 哦, 妈的! - 真他妈的?
- Shit! - Let's get out of here!
- 操. - 我们赶快走.
You all right, man?! Oh, shit!
你还好吗? 哦，见鬼!
[ All Yelling ] We got to get him to a hospital, dawg!
赶快送他去医院
Keys? Where are the keys? Get the fuckin'car!
钥匙? 汽车钥匙在哪儿? 快上车!
[ Yelling ] I got to put pressure on it! I got to put pressure on it!
老兄快按住这里.
- Try not to think about it! - He shot his fuckin' dick off!!
- 放轻松一点. - 他把自己的鸡巴打飞了!
Did I?! Man, shut the fuck up, man!
- 真的? - 老兄，你闭嘴行不行!
Future, take Gratiot to McDougall! I live here too!
- Future, 带他去 McDougall. - 我也住在那里.
I know how to get there! Then fuckin' get us there then!
- 我知道怎么去. - 那就他妈的快带我们去!
Rabbit's gonna teach me  how to write rhyme!
Rabbit会教我怎么来写歌
What the fuck were you doin'  with a gun anyway, man?!
不管怎么样，你拿枪干什么?
What the fuc kwere you doin'  with those motherfuckers?!
你他妈的和那帮傻B混在一起干什么?
- You know I had  a show tomorrow night!  - Calm the fuck down!
- 你知道我明天晚上有个演出! - 冷静点!
What arey'all trippin' about?! M!C! Bob!
你们吵什么? M.C. Bob.
What?! M!C! Bob!
什么?
Man, what are you  talkin' about?!  Is that a good name?!
- 老兄你在说什么? - 这是不是个好名字?
What's wrong  with Cheddar Bob?!  I like M!C! Bob!
－ Cheddar Bob这个名字有什么问题? － 但是我喜欢Mc Bob
Right?! Yeah! M!C! Bob!
- 是吗? - 是 M.C. Bob.
[Wink] I'm the one that got that  fat man out offlippin'burgers.
[Wink] 是我让那个胖子不要再卖肉饼
Really? Yeah. Now Roy's gotta interview him down atJLB.
- 真的? - 是的，Roy在JLB采访了他
And I'm gonna be there. Oh, it's finna be on.
都是我得努力.
So the doctor said  that he hit an artery, but he's gonna be okay!
医生说他射中了动脉， 不过现在没事了
Oh, yeah! That's good, man! Where you been?!
哦，这太好了 你要去哪里？
Prayin'! Is he all right?! Yeah! It's cool!
Prayin. - 他没事情了吧? - 没事了.
Let's go!
我们走吧.
Wink was just tellin' us how  he got in with Roy Darucher!
Wink 告诉我们他怎么给Roy Darucher做事.
Yeah. Shit's hot, man.
听起来不错哦.
[ Sol George ]  He doin' an interview  down atJ LB!
[Sol George] 他在JLB采访做过采访.
Why you even listenin'  to this clown?!
你们怎么会听这个小丑的话?
What?! You heard me.
- 什么? - 你听到了吧.
Clown! [Turning Key, Engine Dead]
小丑.
Man, I don't even know why  you got to be all like that.
我不知道你们这帮家伙为什么这样?
This is a good deal for him! This shit is for real!
对他来说是个好买卖 是最实在的
Oh! It's for real?!
是真的吗?
- Like that time you said  your cousin worked for Dr. Dre?  - [ Snickering ]
我记得上次你说你兄弟替Dr.Dre工作?
Or like that time you were  real tight with that intern  in Russell Simmons' office?!
或者上次你说 你和在Russell Simmons办公室的人很熟悉?
- [ Laughing ] - Or how about the time--
或者那一次...
Man, shut the fuck up!
你他妈的给我闭嘴!
Why you always  givin' me shit, man?!
为什么你总是看我不顺眼?
I mean, is it because I'm makin' moves?!
是因为我现在混的不错吗?
Or is it because your ass  is stuck hosting battles  for, like, two years?!
还是你在那个破地方呆了2年而无所作为?
- You're a fuckin' loser!  - Who the fuck you callin' a loser?!
- 你他妈的是个失败的家伙 - 你他妈叫谁是失败者?
Chill, man! Chill!  How can you guys fight  about this shit now?!
冷静! 冷静点! 你们为什么还为这些狗屁争吵?
I know whatyou're trying  to do with our group, bitch!
我知道你要对我们做什么,臭小子!
Cheddar's layin' up in the fuckin' hospital and you guys want to fight about this?!
Cheddar Bob还住在医院里 你们竟然还为这些东西而争吵
So fuckin' stupid!
真他妈的愚蠢.
[ Wink] Forget this car, ""B!"
[Wink] 忘了这辆吧, "B."
I'll giveyou a ride to work in the morning!
我明天早上会来接你上班.
[Jimmy] Didyou win at bingo tonight? No!
[Jimmy] - 今天晚上你赌博赢拉吗? - 没有.
You record your demo yet?!
你录制了你的母带?
What happened to you?!
你怎么了?
Cheddar Bob had an accident! He's fine! I'm fine!
Cheddar Bob 出了点事. 现在他没事了
You and your friends!
这就是你和你的朋友
Mom, don't start, please!
妈请你不要那么说
It's been a long fuckin' night!
我受够了.
Tell me about it!
和我说说怎么回事.
Me and Greg are havin' problems!
我和Greg也有问题了
- He found out about the eviction?! - No!
- 他知道房租的事了? - 不是.
The settlement check ain't comin'?! No, it's comin'.
- 支票还没有到是吗? - 不，快到了
It's comin'! It's our-- It's our sex life!
就快到了. 是我们的... 是我们性的生活
Mom, I don't want to hear this shit!
妈，我不想听这些狗屁.
I mean, it's good! It's real good!
他很好，非常好
But he just doesn't like-- Mom, I don't want to hear this!
- 他就是不喜欢... - 妈，我不想听这些东西
Greg won't go down on me! Mom!
- Greg 不太接受我。 - 妈!
Hey, Sol. You everwonder whatpointyou gotta just say, "Fuck it, man'"?
嗨，Sol.你曾有那种感觉吗？ 就想说"操它的"
Like when you gotta stop livin' up here and start livin' down here?!
你想有这种水平的生活... 却还活在这种水平
It's 7:30 in the morning, dawg!
现在是早上7点半，老兄
Yo, thank your mom  for the car, dawg!  A'ight!
谢谢你用车送我来！ - 不客气
Man, I'm gettin'  so sick and tired
" 老兄，我真的操他妈的累坏了"
Offuckin' with this steel
" 每天和这臭钢铁打交道 "
They only give us 30 minutes  to eat lunch and chill
" 他们只给我们30分钟吃午饭和休息 "
Mybod ya chin'  just to get a buck
" 我的身体它妈的一定会搞垮 "
I'm sick of eatin' this shit  offthis fuckin' lunch truck
" 我真的是无法忍受 吃这个他妈的午餐车上的垃圾 "
Nasty-ass food  I'm in a nasty-ass mood
" 肮脏的食物让我快要疯掉 "
I should have called in sick  Shit, I had somethin' to do
" 我应该打电话去请病假， 去做自己该做的事情 "
I can't believe I'm hearin'  all this ravin' and rantin'
" 我不敢相信我能听到 这个泼妇的胡言乱语 "
From Vanessa up here  at the New Detroit Stampin'
" 来自这个底特律工厂的Vanessa  "
You needto get your food  and take your ass back to work
" 你最好赶快吃完， 赶快抬起屁股回去工作 "
You're dreamin' if you think  them corny-ass raps will work
" 你在妄想这些乡巴佬会理睬你的话 "
Look aty'all  Standin'out here freezin'  like dumb fucks
"看你们只会像哑巴一样僵死在这里 "
Rappin' away for food  off this raggedy lunch truck
" 只会在这里Rap数落餐车发泄情绪 "
Who want what  Who pumped up  to get rolled up
" 谁会在乎你 跳出来放的狗屁 "
I spit venom  in every direction  Soak some up
" 让我来让你们每个人清醒一下 "
Look at this fat-ass nigga  Sloppy sucker
" 看看这个胖黑鬼 "
You an ugly motherfucker  Yourpop should have  wore a rubber
" 你真它妈的长得好丑, 你的脸上最好带上面具 "
Stop rhymin'  Keep your day job, Vanessa
" 别再抱怨了 去做你的事情吧, Vanessa "
Next time, leave that bullshit  home on the dresser
" 下次把这些屁话带回家去说 "
Speaking of dresses  Take a look at Paul the fruitcake
"说到衣服 看看 我们可爱的Paul
When you travelyou probably    pack panties in your suitcase
" 你旅行的时候也许只会带上妇孺的衣服 "
Made out oflace  from Victoria's Secret
" 有人说出你的花边新闻 "
I f ten men came i n a cup  you'd probably drink it
" 就算有10个男人想和你搞,你也会义不容辞 "
Okay folks  Enough with the gayjokes
好了，各位.. . 同性恋的笑话已经说够了
Especially from a gay broke  bitch yourself, eh, loc
尤其是这个本身就是同性恋的小子 对吧, 嗯, loc "
Who is this--  His style is doo-doo
他是... " 他的造型很酷 "
You've worked here  longer than me and I get  paid more than you do
" 你在这里做的比我久 却赚的比我少 "
Serious, man!  Dawg, take a seat
说什么啊. " 老兄,坐稳了 "
What's this guy  standin' in line for  He ain't got money to eat
" 你们整排站着要做啥？ 他可是连吃饭的钱都没有 "
Check this out  Yo,yo
" 来吧 呦, 呦 "
This guy cashed his whole check  and bought one Ho-Ho
" 这小子全身都找遍了 但是只找到一毛钱 "
[ Laughing ]  Fuckin' homo, little maggoy  You can't hack it
" 操同性恋, 你这个顽固不化的东西 "
Paul's gay, you're a faggot
" Paul是同性恋, 你却是蠢货 "
At least he admits it . Don't even risk it
" 至少他还敢承认, 不会去掩饰 "
- This guy's starvin' to death  Someone get him a biscuit  - [ Laughing ]
" 这个小子快要饿死了 谁能给他块饼干 "
I don't know what  they told you, Mike
" 我不知道他们怎么告诉你的, Mike "
You must have had them cornrows rolled too tight
" 你一定总是让大家讨厌的家伙 "
This job, you wanna quit   But you can't
" 你想辞职，但你却不能这么去做 "
You've worked at this plant so long, you're a plant
" 你在这里呆的太久了 你的脑子也已经生锈了 "
Look atyour goddamn boots For Christ sakes
" 看在上帝的份上看看你他妈的 那双烂鞋子 "
- They're startin' to grow roots  - [ Laughing ]
" 我的天啊，都快要长出'根'了 "
On this mike you get faded
" mike你已经过时了 "
-You look like a pissed-off rappe who never made it - [ Crowd ] Ooh
" 你像个破落的一败涂地的Rapper "
Hey,wh you fuckin'  with the gay guy, ""G"
" 你跟这同性恋小子在做甚麽, "G" "
When really you're the one  who's got the H!I!V!
" 你真的很像得了HIV(爱滋病) "
[ Crowd ] Ooh!  Man, I'm done with this clown   He's soft
" 我不跟这小丑瞎掰，因他太「软」了 "
Fuck it, I'll let homegirl   finish you off
" 操他的，这个家庭主妇就能解决了你 "
That's the only wayyou comin'  Hey, lookin' for your brother?!
嘿
I was! [ Vanessa Continues, Indistinct ]
在找你哥哥吗? -- 我本来是的....
Do you want to  do somethin' tonight?!
你今晚有事吗?
Are you askin' me out  on a date,Jimmy Smith,Jr.?!
你想约我出去吗, Jimmy Smith, Jr.?
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I am!
是啊, 事实上我是想如此.
Why don't you take me somewhere now?!
你为何不现在就带我走?
Come on!
走吧.
Where are we going?!
我们去那里?
You were so good outside!
你刚才在外面表现不错.
- In line at a lunch truck?! - Yeah! And at the Chin Tiki the other night?!
- 刚才在午餐车那里? - 是的. 那天晚上你在Chin Tiki也棒极了?
And that demo thing with Wink?!
和Wink谈的关于录母带的事怎么样了?
You're gonna get a deal soon!
你一定能马上签约的
[ Whispers ] I feel it!
我有这个预感
You was in the parkin' lot the other night?!
那晚你也在那儿?
My friends think you're crazy!
我的朋友认为你是个疯子
Yo, your friends  don't even know me!
但你朋友根本就不了解我
[ Knocking On Door] [D.J. Iz ] Man, ain't nobodyhere.
里面不会有人的.
[Future ] I can't believe  they sent him home already.
[Future] 真不敢相信医院说早把他送回来了
If you ain't got insurance,  the medical establishment  will fuckyou up!
如果你不买保险的话 医疗机构才不会管你的死活
Where the fuck else  would he be?! Just thank God he's alive!
- 他到底他妈的去哪里了? - 上帝保佑他还活着
[ Scoffs ] No! Thank God he didn't  shoot his fuckin' dick off!
不，感谢上帝他没有打飞自己的老二
That's why brothers need  to sign themselves a deal!  I'm tellin' you!
所以这就是为什么很多兄弟 会去签社会福利的原因
Record labels supply niggas  with the benefits they need!
社会福利能给我们一些救济金
Dawg, if we sign us  a deal, you can take  the motherfuckin' benefits!
喂,如果我们去的话, 你可把它妈的救济金全部拿去.
We talkin' Bentleys and Benjamins, not Blue Cross and Blue Shield!
我们在谈 Bentleys 和 Benjamins, 不是 Blue Cross 和 Blue Shield.
I don't give a fuck  about none ofthat!
对那些我没有什么狗屁意见.
I just wanna hear   ThreeAndA Thirdon the box,  know what I'm sayin'?
我只想听到3-1-3是最好的 知道我的意思吗?
One of them strong songs on J LB, you know?!
我们有力的声音在J LB, 明白吗?
We need to save that shit up, put it into savings bonds!
留着那些屁话吧, 我们要做的是积攒些资金
We can build our own studio-- Savings bonds?!
- 来建立我们自己的音乐工作室... - 积攒资金?
Let me askyou a question, dawg.
老兄，我有个问题.
How the fuck are we brothers?! We need fine bitches and phat rides,
我们还算是兄弟吗? 我们需要漂亮妞和好车,
- No goddamn savings bonds! - That's all we ever do, man, is talk shit!
- 而不是去存它妈的钱. - 我们所说的都是讲些鸟话.
""We need to get fine bitches and phat rides!"
"我们需要漂亮妞和好车!"
""No, what we need to do is put our money in savings bonds!"
"不,我们所要做的就是存钱."
""No, what we need to do is get our songs on J LB!"
"不, 我们应先到JLB录首歌."
Man, shut the fuck up! All of us never do shit about nothin'!
去它妈的全都给我闭嘴. 我们什么有意义的事情都没做
We're still broke as fuck and live at home with our moms!
我们仍一无所有 还是待在家中陪咱们的老妈
Yo, I'm outta here!   I'll catch you guys later!
我要走了. 我们待会见.
Man, getyo' mad, ramblin' ass in the car! [ Laughs ] Yeah!
老兄,别生气,去车上消消气! 好.
I hope you get a new ride soon!  Maybe for that  birthday trippin' ass!
希望你马上有辆新车. 或许来个生日旅行
I'm gonna call yo mama, see what I can work out! [ Laughing ]
我会打电话给你老妈 看看我能不能搞定.
- [ Future ] I got shotgun, Shabba! - [D.J. Iz Laughing]
[Future] 我有霰弹枪, Shabba.
Man, why you pretendi n' to be asleep?!
你干嘛假装在睡觉?
Yo, I seen you  out the window, Bob!
我在窗外看到你了， Bob.
I didn't feel like talkin'!
我现在不想讲话.
Why not?!
为什么?
I didn't want them  makin' fun of me!
我不想他们拿我当笑柄.
Do you know what  I'm sayin', Rabbit?
你知道我的意思吗, Rabbit?
Yeah! You do?!
- 是的. - 你真的知道?
M!C! Bob!
M.C. Bob.
Hey, Rabbit! Where ya been?!
嗨, Rabbit. 你上哪儿去了?
You call him Rabbit, too?! I gave him  that nickname!
你也叫他Rabbit? 是我给他起的这个绰号
Stop it! N-No, I did! When he was little,
天啊. 我在他小的时候帮他取的
he had buckteeth and big ears-- [ Giggling ]
他有对大门牙，一双大耳朵...
He was so cute!
他那时候好可爱喔.
""Wike a wittle wabbit!" Right, baby?! [ Laughing ]
"活生生的像一只兔子." 对吗, 宝贝?
I got some good news-- You brought her to my fuckin' moms?!
- 我有些好消息... - 你带她来我家干什么?
What the fuck?!
搞什么鬼啊?
I invited her to my show! She said we had to come and get you!
我邀请她去我的秀 她说要一起过来接你的.
What was I supposed to do?! Look!
我能怎么办呢?
I been helpin' Al find a photographer for her book!
我在帮她的书找个摄影师
All she keeps tellin' me is how much she really likes you, man!
她一直在告诉我她有多么的喜欢你
Damn! Now, check this, dawg!
操! 现在听着,老兄.
I heard from my man Roy today!
Roy 今天跟我说了.
Now, he's gonna be down to J LB tomorrow night!
明天晚上他要在JLB做个面试.
Doin' an interview with  Big O and shit! So what?! So what?!
他要给 big o 做个采访 - 那又怎样 又怎样?
I dropped it! I told him  about your skills, man!
我搞定了!我告诉了他你的杰出才能.
I said,Jimmy Rabbit's your man!  He said, bring him down!!!
我说, Jimmy Rabbit就是你想要得人! 他说,带他来看看
and let me see what he can do!
让我看看他的本事.
Look, man, if everything  goes well, you could be flowin'  down 54 Sound next week!
如果一切顺利， 你下星期可以当歌手了
Now, can you get your shit together in time?!
你可不可以准时到那儿呢?
Yeah! I can do it!
好. 我会的.
My bad, man! Oh, no problem, dawg!
不好意思. 没事,兄弟
[Snaps Fingers ] Big time,Jimmy!
要准时喔, Jimmy.
Why'd you take off?!
你刚才为什么离开?
I don't really live here! So?! Why'd you take off?!
- 我其实不是住在这里. - 那么?你刚才为什么离开?
I just--
我只是...
You don't have to be embarrassed about where you live,Jimmy!
你不用为自己住在那里感到尴尬, Jimmy.
I don't live here!
我不住这里!
What's up with you and Wink?!
你怎么和Wink一起?
He's helpin' me get my book together!
他在帮我出版我的书
Usin' his connections!
利用他的一些关系.
Same way he's helpin' you out!
就像帮你一样.
So--
所以...
You probably have to stay home tonight, huh?!
你今晚可能得待在家里，对吧?
Yeah, I should work on some songs for my demo!
是啊， 我得为我的试唱练一下歌.
Okay!
好吧.
Palms are sweaty
"Palms are sweaty "
Sweaty already,  moms's spaghetti, he's nervous
"Sweaty already, moms's spaghetti, he's nervous "
Keeps on forgetting  what he wrote down
"Keeps on forgetting what he wrote down "
He opens his mouth  Words won't come out
"He opens his mouth Words won't come out "
The clock's run out
" The clock's run out "
Turnin'and turnin'
" Turnin'and turning "
You only get one shot One shot, one shot
" You only get one shot One shot, one shot "
Opportunity-tunity lifetime
" Opportunity-tunity lifetime "
Lose yourself   Lose yourself, lose yourself
"Lose yourself Lose yourself, lose yourself "
Turnin'and turnin'
" Turnin'and turning "
You only get one shot  One shot, one shot
" You only get one shot One shot, one shot "
Opportunity- tunity lifetime, turn
" Opportunity-tunity lifetime, turn "
You know your mom's getti n' evicted?!
你知道你老妈房租到期了吗?
Says right here!
就在这里.
""Tenant must vacate the premises!!!
"由于未依照合约付房租...
due to non-payment of rent!"
租住期终止."
You know about this? [Stephanie ] Morning.
你知道这件事吗? - 早上好.
Sweetie, you want some cereal?!
甜心, 你要些麦片吗?
I was just talkin'toy our precious son  about this eviction situation.
我正在和你的宝贝儿子谈论欠房租的事.
You plan on tellin' me about this, huh?!
你不想让我知道这件事吗?
Oh, honey, th-that was just a mistake!
甜心, 那仅是场误会而已
You're a fuckin' liar! Hey, man!
你是个它妈的骗子. 喂, 小子!
No, no. Stay out ofthis, Rabbit.
不. 这事你不要管, Rabbit.
It's okay, don't worry! I'm takin' care of--
没关系的，不用担心， 我会去处理的...
- Don't! - [ Screams ]
滚开!
Fuck, man! What the fuck is your problem?!
操你的! 你想干什么?
You don't touch my mother, man.  Just stay out of it!  Stay out of it!
- 你少碰我老妈.小子 - 不关你的事.
I'm out of here!  Can't go out with  someone like you!
我要走了. 我无法跟像你这样的人在一起
Are you gonna let him just talk to you like this?!
你就让她这么说你吗?
- With two homeless kids! - [ Roaring, Screaming ]
和2个无家可归的小孩一起.
Rabbit! Jimmy, no! No!
Rabbit.! Jimmy, 不要! 住手!
Rabbit! Jimmy! Jimmy, please!
Rabbit! Jimmy! Jimmy, 不要!
[ Grunts ] Stop it!
住手!
Stop it! Stop!
全都住手!
- Fuckyou! - [Lily Crying]
操你妈!
- Rabbit! Don't! - [ Groans ] - Fuckyou!
Rabbit! 不要! - 你他妈的!
Stop it! Stop it, Rabbit!
别打了! 别打了, Rabbit.
[Rabbit] Oh, my God. Lily. Come here, baby.
[Rabbit] 哦，我的天. Lily. 过来，宝贝.
Come here!
过来.
It's okay.
没事了.
Come here, baby! Come here!
过来，宝贝. 过来
It's okay!
好了.
It's okay! [ Sighing ]
没事了.
It's over! It's over, baby!
没事了 宝贝.
Yo, what up, doe?!
怎么了?
Alex just called! I got  one of my friends to take pictures  ofher when she gets offwork!
Alex刚才给我电话. 我有个朋友等她下班了去接她拍照
So she needs a ride! You know, that's why she called!
她要人去接她. 所以她打电话过来.
- Yo, can you drive?! - I don't care! I'll drive!
- 恩, 你能去吗? - 我会去的.
The others be here in a minute,  so's my uncle can drop 'em off  on the way to work .
其他人马上就来, 我叔叔能够载他们一程
Hey! I heard that your battlin' tomorrow night!
我听说你明晚要去参加比赛.
- I'm doin' what?!  - Someone told me Future  signed you up at The Shelter!
- 我要去怎样? - 有人告诉我future已帮你报名了
- Who told you that?! - [Knocking On Door]
- 是谁告诉你的?
- [DoorOpening] - Yo, what up, dawg? - What up, dawg?
你们怎么样?
[ Wink ] Wipe your feet, dawg.  I ain't gonna wipe anyfeet.
[Wink] 把鞋子擦干净.
Hey, where yo' mama at?! Workin', dawg!
嗨,你妈呢? 上班去了.
Yo, did you sign me up  to battle tomorrow night  at the fuckin' Shelter?!
是你替我报名参加明晚的比赛吗?
[ Chuckles ] What?!  You heard me. Don't play  fuckin'stupid with me, man.
- 什么? 别把我当傻瓜.
Did you sign me up?! [ Sighs Deeply ] J immy--
你它妈的有没有替我报名? - Jimmy...
You know Papa Doc won last week, so he'll be defending his title!
你知道上星期Papa Doc 赢了 他会卫冕他的头衔.
You gotta try to take that shit from him, man!
你一定得设法打败他，老兄
You win battles, you get respect-- I don't give a fuck, man!
- 你一旦蠃了比赛 你得到大家尊敬... - 我才不管那些!
I'm sick ofyou always thinkin' you know what's best for me, dawg!
你好像总是知道什么才是对我有利的 我真是讨厌透了
You ain't my fuckin' father! I'm a grown man!
你不是我它妈的老爸. 我已经是成人了.
Look,Jimmy, I know-- LookJimmy nothin'! Fuckyou!
- 嗯, Jimmy, 我知道... - 别再说了!
I told you not to fuckin' sign me up! What the fuck?!
早告诉你不要替我报名的 你想干什么?
You wanna fight me now, huh?!  Yo, you ain't the Future  of shit, bitch!
- 你想打架吗? - 你才不是什么未来的希望!
You just  David fuckin' Porter!
你只是个他妈的看大门的.
Hey, come on, fellas.
好了，两位.
You know what?!
你知道吗?
Do what the fuck you wanna do, man!
你他妈爱做什么就去做什么吧.
Cause I don't  give a shit anymore!
我已不在乎那些了.
I really fuckin' don't!
老子它妈的不管了.
So you comin' to JLB tonight?! I don't know, man!
你晚上会到JLB来吗? 我不知道.老兄
[Rap On Radio ] I look like crap!
我看起来太憔悴了.
Ifwe knew it was today, I wouldn't have never gone out drinking!!!
早知道是今天
afterthe show last night.  [Wink] I could always reschedule.
我昨晚上就不会去喝酒了. [Wink] 我们一定要按计划.
No, no, no, no, no. I want to do it.
不不 我会去的
Yeah! You want to do it?! I want to do it! Yeah!
- 你现在还是要去? - 我现在要去. - 好.
When are we gonna see  this little pictorial  in a magazine, Alex?!
我们什么时候能够看到那些图片杂志, Alex?
Pictorials for Playboy, fool! In fashion, it's ""editorial!"
只有花花公子才有图片,白痴 在时装上面,是影集
God damn, Frederick Douglass,  will you shut the fuck up?!  It's for her book, man!
- 操你的, Frederick Douglass, 你他妈的就不能闭嘴? - 那是她出的书.
- So she can get a job! - That's one book  I'd definitely read.
- 她才能找到工作. - 我一定会去看得.
[D.J. Iz] That'd be the only one.
[DJ. Iz] 那一定很棒.
Don't forget this! Thanks, guys!
不要忘记这个. 谢啦.
- See ya. - Bye.
- 再见. - 拜拜.
- Can't keep runnin'away    - Want me to come up?!
你要我上去吗?
- That's okay  - Can't keep runnin'away
不要紧的.
Mom!
妈
[ Moans ] Mom, come on! Get up!
好了, 起来吧
Come on! [ Sighs Deeply ]
起来.
Come on! [ Grunts ]
来
Greg left me! Yeah?!
Greg离开我了. 是吗?
[Lily Babbling] He left me!
他离开我了.
[ Grunts ] Oh! Damn!
哦. 妈的!
Come on! Get up! Hi, honey!
快起来. 嗨...亲爱的.
It's okay, Lily. It's okay, honey.
不要紧的, Lily. 不要紧的, 宝贝.
His settlement check came in!
他的支票到了.
[ Chuckling ] His settlement check came in!
他的支票到了
And now that he's got money,
他现在有钱了,
he can't be with somebody like me anymore!
他已经不要我了.
[ Chuckling ] It's Thursday! I got-- I got--
今天星期四. 我要去...
I gotta go to bingo! Maybe he'll be there!
我要去赌场. 或许他会在那里.
You're goin' nowhere! Better off without him!  Stop it!
- 你那都别想去. 他不在最好. - 住手!
Stop it! It's your fault he left me!
住手. 都是你的错他才会抛弃我
You ruined it! You ruined it! You fucked it all up for me!
是你搞砸的! 都是你把所有东西搞得一团糟
Who's gonna want me now?! Who's gonna want me?! Where are we gonna live?!
现在谁还会要我呢? 谁还会要我呢? 我们到哪里去住?
We don't have any money! We don't have anything!
我们没有钱 我们什么都没有!
What am I gonna do?!
我该怎么半?
- What am I gonna do? - What are you gonna do?!
- 我该怎么半? - 你要怎么半?
Lily's out there by herself right now!
lily现在还在外面呆着
Why doyou got to be like this?!
你为什么要这样?
What did we ever do toyou?! Get the fuck out ofhere!
- 我们又对你做错了什么? - 你它妈的滚出去.
Get the fuck out of my house!
滚出我的房子!
We're goin' next door, okay?! We're gettin' out ofhere! Come on!
我们到邻居家去,好吗? 我带你离开这里 来吧
What floor is J LB on?! Twenty-eight!
JLB在第几层楼? 28楼.
Thankyou! You're welcome!
谢谢. 不用客气.
I 'm looki n' for Wi nk Harris! Who?!
我来找 Wink Harris. 谁?
He's supposed to be here  with Roy Darucher!
我想他和 Roy Darucher 在一起.
Oh, I think they're  all down in Studio ""B!"
我想他们在B号录音室
All right! Thank you!  Mm-hmm!
好,多谢
You finally got your record on the radio!  How does it make you feel, man?!
你的唱片终于发行了, 你有什么感受吗?
Oh, man, that's much love!  I want to thank you  and WJ LB, man!!!
哦, 太多了我要谢谢大家和JLB...
forlookin'out forme like that, dawg, so much love.
太多要感谢的人了
I'm tryin'to put Detroit-- the east side, forsure-- on the map.
我想通过我让大家认识底特律
Know what I'm sayin'? And we gonna do it for real.
知道我们说什么吗? 我们不是开玩笑的.
We'll get a pipeline to come through here, and the industry'll look at us...
我希望整个唱片界都能认识我们
Wait, wait, wait-- [ Screams ] J i m my!
等下,等下... Jimmy!
Stop it! Stop it!
住手! 住手!
I 've seen you flippin' burgers, baby, I know I have!
我看到你过你卖肉饼!
[ Chuckles ] Yeah, I did that, man!
是的 我是做过
I thought I recognized your face, baby!
我想我记得你的脸
[ Alex, Screaming ] Stop it! Fuckin' stop it! Please! Please stop!
住手! 拜托你别打了
Stop it!Jimmy, stop it! [ Grunting, Groaning ]
别打了.Jimmy, 住手
-Jimmy-- - How long you been in the game, baby?!
你唱了多少年了?
- Aw, man, fifteen years! - [ Grunting, Punch Landing ]
大约15年
You represent real hard for the 3-1 -3!
你将代表3 1 3...
For sure, man, I 'm doin' it! I'm doin' it fory'all, man!
当然,兄弟,我会的 我做这些都是为了你们
This is for Detroit! 3-1 -3, baby! Love!
这是为了底特律. 希望你们永远都喜欢313
Thank you, Mrs! Helgeland! Anytime,Jimmy!
- 谢谢, Helgeland太太. - 不用客气, Jimmy.
Have a good night! Mm-hmm!
晚安.
Hey, did you have fun?! Mm-hmm!
你玩的高兴吗? 嗯
Yeah! I know!
是的,我知道
Okay, baby! I want you to go inside!  I want you to lock the door, okay?!
宝贝,我要你马上进去 把门锁好 ,好吗?
Listen to me! Go inside, lock the door!
听我说. 进去,关好门.
I'll be in in a minute, okay?! Okay!
我马上就回来，好吗?
Okay! Go!
好.去吧.
Go!
走啊!
Yo, what up, bitch?!
怎么了,臭小子
You ready to get knocked out, doe?!
你准备好挨揍了吗?
[Lyckety-Splyt Chuckles ] Wink said you lived  in a trailer with your mom.
Wink说你跟你妈住在拖车里
[ Laughing ] But we didn't believe him!
但我们不相信他说的话
Come on, Elvis. Get up.
来啊, 猫王 站起来
Get up, bitch!
站起来,臭婊子
[Booming Rap Continues ] [Man ] Getyo'faggot ass up and fight.
爬起来扁我们啊.
[ Scoffs ] What?! What the fuck is you lookin' at?!
你他妈的看什么看?
Get down, you faggot! Get down!
起来啊,臭小子!
-J immy! - [ Grunting ]
Jimmy!
Come here! Get the fuck up there!
来啊,过来.
Stop it!
住手!
Fight me, you punk-ass bitch!
过来打我啊, 你这欠扁的贱人!
- What the fuckyou gonna do?! - [ Grunts, Groans ]
你他妈的想干什么?
I could end your shit right now,  and nobody would even miss your ass!
我现在就可以干掉你这白痴 没有人会记得你
No, no, no! No, no! Don't do this!
不, 不, 不要这麽做
Come on. He's done.
走吧..已经够他受的了
- Free World, motherfucker! - [ Coughing ]
Free World, 操你老母.
[ Lyckety ] Don't forget to come to The Shelter tomorrow night! [ Laughing ]
别忘了明晚要来叁加比赛啊!
[ Papa Doc ] Yeah, see you down there you li'l rabbit!
[Papa Doc] 明天见啊, rabbit!
Jesus! What happened toyou?!
老天，你是怎么了?
I fell! You fell!
- 我不小心摔的. - 你摔倒了?
I fell!
我就是摔倒了.
Come on in! I'll makeyou something to eat!
进来，我来给你弄点吃的.
What?!
什么?
I'm your mother! I want to makeyou something to eat!
我是你母亲. 我想要给你弄点吃的.
What's the big deal?!
这还要商量吗?
I thoughtyou wanted me out!
我还以为你要我滚蛋
You want the fuckin' pancakes or not?!
你到底要不要吃煎饼?
What's gotten into you?!
你怎么了?
We're not gettin' evicted! Why not?!
我们不会被逐出了 为什么不会?
I went to bingo!
我去赌博了.
And I won!
而且我蠃了!
Thirty-two hundred!
3200美元!
- You're kidding me! - [ Laughing ] Nope!
你是在开玩笑的吧!
Our luck's finally changing around here!
我们终于时来运转.
Did you mean whatyou said about doin' that demowith Wink?!
你还记得你说要跟Wink去录音的吗?
No!
不
I'm gonna do it on my own!
我自己会去做
You know, Rabbit?! I think that's the best way!
你知道吗, Rabbit? 我想那才是你应该做的
Hey, Smith!
喂, Smith!
Hey! Smith!
喂! Smith!
Areyou all right?! I fell down some steps!
你没事吧? 我从楼梯上摔下来了.
You been doin' much better here! You still want those extra shifts?!
你现在做的好多了. 还想多干点赚点外快吗?
Yeah! You got 'em! I need you to work tonight! I'm a man short!
好啊. 我今晚要你加班. 我现在缺人手
Tonight?! Is that a problem?!
今晚? 有问题吗?
No problem! Good!
没问题. 很好.
Go on! Get back to work!
好了，回去工作吧
Hey, Manny!
嗨, Manny!
Thanks!
谢了....
What up?! Shit!
怎么了? 妈的
Waitin' on this slow-ass ride!
等等看谁能捎我一段
What areyou still doin' here?!
你还在这里干什么?
Somebody called in sick, so I'm just fillin' in!
有人生病请假了,所以我来顶替
She ain't waitin' on me! I'll be back!
- 她好像不是在等我. - 我马上回来.
What doyou want?! I wanted to say good-bye!
- 你来干什么? - 我是来道别的
I'm goin' to New York!
我要去纽约了...
Yeah?! And--
是吗?还有呢...
[ Sighing ] Can I giveyou a ride?! There's some things--
要我载你一程吗? 有些...
No, I'm cool! Workin' overtime!
不，谢了... 加班呢.
Saving up for  something special?!  Yeah!
为某种特别原因在存钱吗? 是的.
Studio time!
录音费用.
Good!
好啊
Good for you!
那很好
I was hopin' to seeyou at The Shelter tonight!
我希望今晚能见到你
But if you're afraid--  I'm not afraid  ofthem guys!
- 但是如果你害怕的话... - 我一点也不怕他们.
I didn't say you were!
我没有说你会害怕.
Bye!
再见.
Hey, Paul! Would you mind covering for me for a couple hours?!
嘿！ Paul， 你可否帮我挡个几个钟头?
Yeah, I can do that! Thanks, man! I oweyou!
好的,没问题. 多谢了,我欠你份人情.
- Hey! It's Rabbit! Hey! - Come on, man!
- 嗨.! 那是 Rabbit.!嗨! - 快点来
[ Cheddar Bob ] Yo, Rabbit, wait up!
Rabbit, 等一下!
What's up, man? What the hell happened toyou?
老兄，怎么啦? 你没事吧?
You straight?! Look at your eye! Yeah, man! I'm fine! Come on!
- 你怎么了? 你看你的眼睛. - 是的，我没事
Wink's sayin'you blew up  'cause Roy Darucher  wouldn't payforyour demo.
Wink说你快气疯了 因为Roy Darucher不愿意支付你的录音费用
He's also sayin' some crazy shit  about him and Alex!
他还说了些有关他跟Alex的鬼话..
We gonna jump those guys again?!
我们还要对付那些家伙吗?
Fuck that! I'm gonna battle 'em!
去他的. 我要去参加比赛.
- For real?! - Yeah!
- 真的吗? - 是的.
Damn! Yo, you guys comin' orwhat?!
你们来还是不来?
Cheddar, I can rip you to a shred of cheddar cheese!
Cheddar,我可以把你切成一片片的干酪.
There's not a better M!C! than me!
这里没有比我更好的M.C
I'm B-Rabbit, bitch. Sting like a bee.
我是B-Rabbit, 婊子. 像蜜蜂一样刺人
Float like a butterfly. What am I?
像蝴蝶一样轻巧. 为什么是我?
So what if I cut a guy?! Did I s-s-stutter, guy?!
如果我砍倒几个呢? 我难道是结巴吗?
Leave you punch drunk From lunch truck to Shelter!
去他妈的冲床 从工厂的餐车来到Shelter.
You never felt the wrath of helter-skelter melt ya,
我的愤怒足够把你给融化掉
got the belt for the welterweight champ!
拳击手准备好了, 该你上场的时候了
You got in with a fake stamp! [ Chuckles ]
你的奖章不过是个假货
Garbage bag full of clothes, still pullin' ho's!
你身上满是垃圾, 倒是能够引起注意
Ripyou from head to toe, from leg to bullet hole!
我要把你从头到脚的撕开成二瓣.
Next gun, pull it slow! And aim at Tha Free World 'foreyou let it go!
下次开枪你要慢一点. 瞄准好 Free World在去开火
Instead of, ""Oh! I just shot my dick head!" [ Laughing ]
不要再说, "哦,我打中我得鸡巴了"
And yes, you do got a big head! I can't call it!
是的,你也许是个"大头",我不能那么叫
Cheddar, where's your wallet?!  You're so drunk, you can  out-drink the Alkoholiks!
Cheddar, 你的钱包呢? 你醉得太厉害了, 你不能再喝酒
Make 'em say, ""Damn! Cheddar's the man!
让他们说, "妈的?cheddar就是那个人"
He needs a can  surgically removed  from his hand--"
他需要个罐子在外科手术中..."
You again?! It look like a fuckin' handicap convention in here!
又是你? 你看起来就像 是个残障人士
- Bunch of crippled motherfuckers.  - Oh, yeah! Don't shoot!
- 一群死残疾佬. - 哦,别开枪!
Hey,yo. Let's get the fuck out ofhere.
各位 我们离开这鬼地方.
Fuck them!
操他的.
Yo, I need to get some privacy, guys!
我有事要跟他单独谈谈.
Can I come?!
我可以跟你一起去吗?
[ Sighs ] Hey, man!
嗨,老兄.
I apologize-- Stop it! Don't do it!
我很抱歉... 停！别说了...
I ain't even trip! But you just make sure!!!
我根本没有在意. 不过你必须保证...
you flip the script on this shit tonight!
你要把那些狗屁都给我搞定.
You understand me?! Hmm?!
你明白我吗?
- Thankyou! - It's on tonight, Rabbit!
- 谢谢你. - 全看你的了, Rabbit.
[ Sighs Deeply] Let's do it!
咱们上吧.
A'ight, a'ight, a'ight, a'ight!
好了,好了!
How you feelin' out there?! You feelin a'ight?!
大家今晚感觉怎么样?
All right, all right, all right, all right!
好了,好了
- Next up is L!C! Lyckety-Splyt! - Slaughter 'em, Lyckety! Slaughter 'em!
- 下一位是 L.C. Lyckety-Splyt. - 宰了他们, Lyckety.
And my man B-Rabbit! B-Rabbit, whereyou at?! B-Rabbit, come to the stage!
还有我的 B-Rabbit. B-Rabbit, 你在那里? B-Rabbit, 到台上来
Where the fuck is B-Rabbit?!
他妈的B-Rabbit在那?
Yo, ""B!" They're callin' your name! You drew Lyckety-Splyt in the first round!
喂, "B." 他们在叫你了. 你和 Lyckety-Splyt 比第一场.
You okay with that? Yeah!
你没问题吧? 没问题.
Don't give a fuck who it is!
我才不管他是谁.
Okay! Where the fuck is B-Rabbit?
Ok. 快上台吧B-Rabbit?
B-Rabbit? What're you sayin', brother?
B-Rabbit? 你在哪儿！上来吧?
Got everybody waitin'.
不要让大家等
All right, let you all know,  it's gonna be blazin'  up in this bitch tonight .
好了,让你们知道他今晚会有多么耀眼.
Got a lot ofdope rappers  comin' to the stage,  and it's gonna be nice.
有这么多rapper歌手来 今天晚上比赛一定精彩.
One ofthese cats  is goin'down a winner  via sweet Papa Doc.
只有一位最后能挑战Papa Doc.
Come to the stage, Rabbit.
快上来, Rabbit.
Come to the stage!
快上台来.!
B-Rabbit, where you at?! Oh, there he is! Come on!
B-Rabbit, 你在那里? 哦,他在这里
All right, make way for the Rabbit.  Let him come through.
All right, 给 Rabbit让个路 让他过来
Come on, let the artist get to the motherfuckin'stage.
你们它妈的别挡到他的路
Come on, man.
来吧.
Al I right, come on up! Come on, B-Rabbit! Let him up, let him up!
快上来, B-Rabbit. 让他上来 让他上来.
You good?! Choose somethin'!
还好吧? 选一面
Heads! Heads?!
头. 头?
- You got it! - All right, my man!
- 你猜对了.
I'm goin' first against  this choke artist here!
我来对付这个哑巴.
Well, baby, you got  enough confidence!  Get serious!
不错你很有信心啊
Okay, doyour thing! Forty-five seconds!
好了,开始把 45秒
Yo, D.J., spin that shit.
DJ.放音乐
[ Drum Track] Free World, okay?
Free World, ok?
Tell you somethin'!
我来告诉你们一些事情...
Check this out. Check this out.
来吧.
Yo! This guy's a choke artist!
呦. 这个人只是个哑巴.
You catch a bad one, you better off shootin' yourself with Papa Doc's handgun @
" 你碰上我算你倒霉, 你最好用Papa Doc的枪给自己做个了解 "
Climbin' up this mountain You're weak, I leaveyou lost without a paddle @
" 爬这坐高山你太嫩了, 我怕你随时都会迷路 "
Floatin'up shit's creek  You ain't Detroit, I'm the "D'
"你只知道四下乱串 掉到河里淹死 你不是底特律的代表,我才是这里的主宰 "
You the new kid on the block 'bout to get smacked back to the boondocks @
" 你在街区里只是个新来的 '和我较量只会把你打回老家 "
Fuckin' Nazi Your squad ain't your type Take some real advice @
" 操他的纳粹 你们的造型实在太逊 应该好好听听得我的意见 "
And form a group with Vanilla Ice
" 去吃你们的香草冰激凌吧孩子 "
And what I tell you  You better use it  This guy's a hillbilly
" 你们这些小子最好听我的, 这些家伙真是乡巴佬 "
This ain't Willie Nelson music
" 你们不配唱Willie Nelson 的音乐 "
Trailertrash, I'll choke you  to your last breath  And have you look foolish
" 拖车里的废物,我要你到咽气也唱不出来 只能活活象个白痴 "
Like Cheddar Bobwhen he shot himself  Silly Rabbit
" 就像 Cheddar Bob 只会给自己身上开枪,蠢兔子 "
I knowwhythey call you that 'Causeyou follow Future
" 我知道他们为什么看不起你 因为你和 Future 一起混 "
Like he got carrots  up his ass crack
" 就像他一样只会用萝卜捅自己屁股 "
And when you acted up  That's when you got  jacked up and act stupid
" 你那种蠢模样 让人看了就很不爽 "
Like Tina Turner  when she got smacked up
" 就像 Tina Turner 正想海扁你一顿 "
I crackyour shoulder blade  You'll get dropped so hard
" 我在你身边的时候, 你想出头比登天还难 "
That Elvis'll start turnin' in his grave
" 连猫王都会气的从坟墓里面爬出来 "
- [ Laughing, Groaning ]   - Now I knowwhythey left you   out in the dark
" 现在我知道他们为什么让你站在黑暗中 "
Take your white ass back across 8 Mile to the trailer park
" 让你的大白屁股照亮回拖车的路 "
Oh, no, oh! Okay, okay, okay. Okay, okay.
哦! 好了,好了.
Very nice, very nice! Let me get that mike, man! Pretty good, pretty good!
非常好，把麦克风给我 非常精彩
Hip-hop 1 01! Hey, Bunny Rabbit! It's your turn, baby!
嗨, Bunny Rabbit. 现在轮到你了
Forty-five seconds! Let this motherfucker feel it!
45 秒 给这些狗娘养的一点颜色.
A'ight?! Yo, D!J!, spin that shit!
好了吗? D.J.放音乐.
- Come on, Rabbit! - Don't choke this time!
- 加油, Rabbit! - 这次不要又哑巴了.
A'ight, look!
好的,看着.
He's chokin'!
他又哑巴了 !
Hey, yo!
嘿，呦
This guy raps like  his parents jerked him  He sounds like Erick Sermon
" 这小子唱起来就好像他父母虐待过他 他以为他能够说得比唱还好听 "
The generic version
" 不过如此而已 "
This crowd looks suspicious  It's all dudes in here  Except for these bitches
" 在这里人都不过是些花花公子, 除拉那些是王八蛋以外 "
You want a German, eh  That's okay, you look like  a fuckin' worm with braids
" 你喜欢谈论德国, 恩,那好, 你就像只会爬的小虫 "
These Leadaz Of Tha Free World rookies Lookie
" 你们这些 Free World 就像多嘴的乌鸦一样 "
How could six dicks be pussies
" 六个鸡巴怎么会去操一个阴户 "
Talkin'bout shit's creek  Bitch,you could be up  piss creek with paddles
" 谈到河流,王八蛋, 你除了会在里面小便还会什么
This deep  You're still gonna sink  You're a disgrace
" 埋你这只小虫这么深就够了, 你这丢脸的家伙 "
Yeah, they call me Rabbit. This is a turtle race
" 是的, 他们叫我 兔子 你最多算是乌龟 "
He can't get with me  spittin' this shit wickedly  lyckety-shot
" 你凭什么来打败我 你这个坏透的臭小子 "
- A spick-a-spickety, Split-Lickety  - Oh, no, no!
" 我比你好上百倍, 快上百倍" - 哦,天啊!
I'm gonna turn around with a smile and walk mywhite ass back across 8 Mile
" 我现在要回去我的8英里街了, 用我得屁眼看着你 "
Oh-h! Oh, oh! Say no mo'! That's what I'm talkin' about!
哦!哦,太棒了! 这才是我所说的!
It's unanimous! Bunny Rabbit goes to the next round!
无可争议的! Bunny Rabbit 进入下一轮!
And Lyckety-- Tell yo' mama I'll be over later!
喂 Lyckety... 帮我问候你老母.
Tell herto save me a plate.
要她去为你祈祷吧.
You killed him! Good shit!
你杀的他片甲不留.真酷.
A'ight, a'ight, a'ight! Hold it, hold it, hold it!
好了, 好了 冷静一点, 冷静一点
Next up, next up, we got, uh-- Ox andStrike.
下一位,, 是,嗯... Ox 和 Strike.
Come to the stage, motherfuckers. We ain't got all day.
快点上来,混蛋 抓紧时间
Yo, Rabbit! [ Laughing ]
呦, Rabbit!
Okay, okay, B-Rabbit. Call it!
好了, B-Rabbit. 你来选.!
Heads! Heads!
头. 头!
Choose! Lotto, it's on you, baby! You first!
你选. Lotto, 你先来吧.
Don't matter none!  DJ!, spin that shit!
没关系. D.J., 转动那玩艺吧!
Oh, look! Oh, he's takin' his shirt off!
哦,看! 他把衣服脱了.
Come on, smack this cat, all right?!
加油, 打倒那病猫,好吗?
[Lotto ] Fuck this coward, dawg.
操他的胆小鬼.
Free World's in  the motherfuckin'house.  What's goin'on, baby?
freeworld在这里，那么会发生什么呢?
Yo, it's time to get rid  of this coward here  once and for all!
现在是给这些懦夫一个教训的时候了
I 'm sick of this  motherfucker!
这个混蛋真让我恶心.
[Man ] Rip it, Lotto. Rip it, baby, rip it! Yeah!
让他安息吧,Lotto!
Yo, I spit a racial slur  Honky, sue me
" 呦, 告诉你白混小子,我要控诉你 "
This shit is a Harlem flick  But the black guy doesn't  die in this movie
" 这里是黑人住宅区 , 这里是我们黑人的天下 "
- [ Cheering ] - Fuckin'with Lotto, dawg  You got to be kiddin'
"你想跟我斗,伙计 你简直就是开玩笑 "
That makes me believe  you really don't have  a interest in livin'
" 我看你真的是好像活腻了 "
You think these niggas gonna  feel the shit you say
" 你认为这些人会喜欢你的满嘴胡言 "
I got a better chance joinin' the K!K!K!
" 我看你还是去加入三k党吧 "
Know some realshit, though  I like you-- that's why  I didn't want to be the one
"好了,老弟虽然你废话多, 我还是喜欢你,我还是不想你为我 "
You commit suicide to  Fuck Lotto  Call me your leader
崇拜到想要去自杀 操他的 Lotto 叫我一声老大 "
I feel bad that  I got to murder that dude  from Leave It To Beaver
" 我真是感觉不好 我想剥了你这小混蛋的皮 "
[ Cheering ]  I used to like that show
"我一直喜欢这里的表演 "
Now you got me in fight back mode. But oh well, ifyou got to go  You got to go
" 不过你现在让我只想和你拼命 不过你要是想走,就赶快滚吧 "
I hate to do this I would love for this shit to last
" 我也不想这么做, 但是我要和你这狗屎比到最后 "
So I'll take pictures of my rear end  so you won't forget my ass
" 我会拍些我屁股的照片 叫你不会忘记我 "
And all is well that ends okay  So I'll end this shit with a ""Fuckyou, but have a nice day"
" 但是话又说回来，那也没有关系 我说"我操你,并祝你有个愉快的一天 "
Whoa, whoa! Okay, okay!
哦 好了.
Can't be bad! Can't be bad!
不错 不错.
- Kill that fucked-up white boy! - That ain't shit! That ain't shit!
- 杀了那个白混小子. - 那只是狗屎..
Settle down, settle down! Give the man a chance!
好了，安静一下. 让我说句话
All right, Bunny Rabbit's up next! All right, B-Rabbit?! You got the mike!
好了, Bunny Rabbit准备开始. B-Rabbit? 拿好麦克风.
It's on you! You know what to do!
全靠你了. 你知道该怎么做.
D!J!! Spin that shit! @@ [ Bass Begins ]
D.J.! 放音乐!
What up?! You got somethin'?!
怎么了? 你要说什么?
- Let me hear somethin'.  - You can't fuck with us! Yeah!
- 那就说啊 - 你操不过我们的.
- Let's see what you got! - Come on, Rabbit!
- 让我看你有什么能耐. - 加油, Rabbit.!
Come on, Rabbit! Get him!
加油, Rabbit! 打败他!
No more here! Nah!
不可能的.
Ward, I thinkyou were a little hard on the Beaver
" Ward, 我想你们的理解好像有点问题 "
So was Eddie Haskell  Wally and Ms! Cleaver
"还有 Eddie Haskell Wally 和你们这些屠夫 "
Who-oa  This guykeeps screamin  He's paranoid
哦! " 这个家伙一直在这里乱叫, 我想他是神经透顶 "
Quick, someone get his ass  another steroid
" 天啊, 他的屁股就像打了类固醇 "
Blah-be-dee, blooh blah
" Blah-de-bee-bee, blah blah Blah-be-dee, blooh blah "
I didn't hear a word you said  hip pity-hoo blah
" 我听不见你在说什么, 都是他妈的废话 "
Is that a tank top  Or a new bra
" 这是件背心 还是你新买的胸罩 "
Look, Snoop Dogg has got a fuckin' boob job
" 你这个四处乱吠的狗也有份狗屎的工作 "
Didn't you listen to  the last round, meathead . Pay attention
" 你听到上一轮的比赛了吗 傻瓜,你给我注意点 "
- You're sayin' the same shi that he said  - I'm gonna fuckyou up!
- " 你和他唱的一样烂 " - 我操你妈!
Matter offact, dawg, here's a pencil Go home, write some shit
" 老兄你最好拿上这支铅笔, 回去写点狗屎出来 "
Make it suspenseful And don't come back until somethin' dope hityou
" 除非你真的有点拿的出来的东西 否则最好不要回来 "
Fuck it, you could take  the mike home with you
" 操它, 你可以把这麦克风拿回去 "
[Crowd] Whoa!  Lookin' like a cyclone hit you
哦! " 你看来就像被狠揍过一样 "
Tank top's screamin'  ""Lotto, I don't fit you"
" 连你的背心都会说 "Lotto, 我不想让你穿 "
You see how far  Them white jokes get you, boys like
" 看看我们白人的笑话是怎么搞你的 "
""How's Vanilla Ice gonna dis you"
" 孩子,想要香草冰淇淋吗 "
Mymotto, fuck Lotto  I'll get the seven digits from  yo'motherfora dollartomorrow
"我得座右铭就是, 操 Lotto 我明天会把你们这7个白痴送还给你们妈妈 "
- [ Cheering ] - [ Future ] Oh! O-Oh! Oh, oh, oh!
- [Future] 哦,哦!
Whoo! [ Laughing ]
哦!
[ Chattering ] It's as real as it feels! It's as real as it feels!
太精彩了!
A'ight, hold on! Hold on! Hold on! That was some close shit!
等会，等会. 真是不分上下阿
Let's see what's poppin'! A'ight, how are you feelin' about Lotto up here?!
让我们来看看 你们觉得Lotto表现如何?
Okay, okay, okay! B-Rabbit!
好，好. B-Rabbit.
Okay. We gonna do this again. We gonna do this again.
好的, 咱们再来一次.
It's hard to judge! A'ight, we'll start with Lotto!
太难下结论了. Lotto的表现如何.
Okay, a lotta love. A lotta love. Lotta love.
好了,不错啊.不错
What about B-Rabbit?!
那么B-Rabbit呢?
"B. '"got more! Sayno more!
不用说了!
B-Rabbit advances  to the next round!
B-Rabbit 进入下一轮.!
He's goin' to the finals!  He's goin' up against Papa Doc!
他进入决赛 他要和Papa Doc一决高下.
That's the way it's goin' down!
这就是我们要看的
A'ight, check this! Check this! We're goin' to have a 1 5-minute intermission!
听好了 我们先休息15分钟.
Make sure you tip  the bartenders and all that! Fifteen minutes, y'all!
大家好好休息下 15分钟
Y'all be back for  the final round, all right?
你已经准备好决赛了,对吗 ?
Yeah, that's all right, 'cause Wink got mo' than seven digits from yo' bitch!
是啊, 但是我们7个白痴却把你的婊子给干了
Yeah! You hit it, kid!
你说的好,小子.
Boom! Boom! Boom! Boom! Ha-ha!
Boom. Boom. Boom. 哈哈
Man, fuck him. Fuck Lyckety, man!
操他的. 操 Lyckety.
Yo, that Leave It To Beaver line almost killed me!
刚才那些话差点要了我的命.
You flipped it on him! You got it, man! You're a fuckin' genius, man!
你反击的太漂亮了. 你做到了,兄弟你真它妈的是个天才
Just make sure you serve  this clown in the next round  for me, please!
下一轮为了我你要好好修理他们.
Whup Papa Doc's ass!  Yeah, he ain't got  no vocabulary!
踢烂 Papa Doc的屁股 是啊,让他无话可说
Areyou worried about what he's gonna say?! What doyou mean?!
你会担心他会说什么吗? 你这话什么意思?
You know, about Wink and that Alex bitch gettin' it on!!!
你知道 Wink 和那个婊子Alex 的事情...
and then, them beatin' you up and givin' you a black eye and shit?!
还有他们揍你,打的你黑眼圈...
- Come on, Cheddar! - Fuck all that! Listen to me, man!
- 不要瞎说, Cheddar! - 让他呆一边去 听说我.
- You makin' history tonight! - [ Chuckling ] It ain't nothin'! You got him!
- 你今晚会创造历史. - 没关系,你打败他了.
- Oh, yeah! - You got this!
- 哦,是啊. - 你做到了.
Oh!Now right beside me  is the championship round.
现在是冠军赛！ 决战的时刻来临了
And yes, believe it's real!
你不会相信这是真的.
It's time! We got Papa Doc!!!
我们有Papa Doc...
and we got B-Rabbit!
和 B-Rabbit.
Now, I don't even have  to stress how important this is!
我真的无法形容这一轮比赛 有多么重要的意义
It's the championship!
这是冠军争夺战!
This motherfucker  is what we came to see! Know what I'm sayin'?!
这就是我们想要看的. 明白我的意思吗?
That's why the fuckwe're in the ""D!" We represent!
这也是我们来此的目的!
We at The Shelter, goddamn it!  It's real! I hopey'all ready!
这是来真的了, 我希望你们都准备好了
This shit is about to be  already crackolatin' up in this bitch!
我们将会看到一场大秀.
A'ight, hold on, hold on, hold on!
稍等，稍等!
Gotta do this coin toss!
我们要以掷钱币决定顺序.
And bein' that Papa Doc is the champion, you get to choose!
Papa Doc 是卫冕冠军,你先来选.
What doyou want to do, heads or tails?! Heads!
你的决定如何, 是人头还是字? 人头.
Heads! [Coin Ringing]
人头
Okay! Who goes first?!
好了. 谁先来?
Let that bitch go first!
我让这臭痞子先
Whoa, ho, ho! Whoa, ho, whoa!
哦,哦, 哦
I can't believe my ears! A lot ofhostility!
我真的是不敢相信我的耳朵. 多么浓的火药味!
Papa got a lot of anger!
Papa 好像很生气!
All right, all right, all right! Hey, check this out!
好了,好了.
We got new rules! We got new rules!
我们有新的规则.
Bein' it's the championship round!
作为冠军争夺赛
Each ofthese cats, they get a minute and a halfapiece!
他们每个人都有1分半钟时间
I don't know what's gonna happen! You ready?!
真不知道会发生什么. 准备好了吗?
You know what to do?! D!J!, kick that shit!
你知道该怎么做? D.J., 放音乐!
[ Crowd Chanting Rhythmically] Fight! Fight! Fight!
上啊!上啊!上啊!
Now, everybody from the 3-1 -3 Put your motherfuckin' hands up and follow me
" 现在，每个来自313的朋友 把你的他妈的手举起来跟着我的节奏..... "
Everybody from the 3-1 -3 Put your motherfuckin' hands up Look, look
" 在3 1 3的每一个人， 全部把你它妈的手都举起来 "
Now while he stands tough  Notice this man did not have his hands up
" 这个白痴站在这里, 可是他没有举起手来 "
This Free World's gotyou gassed up Now who's afraid ofthe big, bad wolf
" 你们Free World算什么东西, 现在谁会去怕你们的鸟帮派 "
One, two, three and to the four
" 1 2 3  ....接着是 4  "
One Pac, 2Pac, 3Pac, four 4Pac, 3Pac, 2Pac, one
" 1 Pac, 2Pac, 3Pac, 4 4Pac, 3Pac, 2Pac, 1 "
You're Pac, he's Pac No Pac, none
" 你是 Pac, 他是 Pac 没有 Pac, 什么都不是 "
This guy ain't no motherfuckin' M!C!
" 他们根本就不是他妈的mc. "
@ I know everything he's got to say against me @
" 我知道他要对我说的每一件事 "
I am white, I am a fuckin' bum I do live in a trailerwith my mom
" 我是白人没错！我也是个痞子 我确实是跟我老妈住在拖车里 "
My boy Future is an Uncle Tom I do got a dumb friend named Cheddar Bob
" 我的朋友Future就像Tom大叔 我是有个傻乎乎的朋友叫Chedder Bob "
Who shoots himself  in his leg with his own gun
" 是的,他用自己枪打中自己的腿 "
I did getjumped  by all six of you chumps
" 我说你们6个人怎么都哑巴了 "
And Wink did fuck my girl I'm still standin' here screamin' ""FuckTha FreeWorld"
" 是的，Wink确实干了我的女友 不过我还是在这里狂喊 "操你的 Free World" "
Don't never try to judge me   Dude, you don't knowwhat  the fuck I been through
" 你要随便评论我,白痴 你根本不知道我经历过什么
But I know something about you  You went to Cranbrook  That's a private school
" 但我知道一些关于你的事 你就读的 Cranbrook是间私立学校 "
What's the matter, dawg  You embarrassed
" 怎么了，小子，你害臊了吗 "
This guy's a gangsta  His real name's Clarence
" 这家伙是个士匪 他的真名叫做Clarence "
Clarence lives at home with both parents, Clarence's parents have a real good marriage
" Clarence 和父母住在一起, Clarence的父母有个很美满的婚姻 "
He don't know how to battle  He's shook
" 他不知道怎么比赛 他在害怕的颤抖 "
Cause ain't no such things as halfway crooks
" 因为没有人会比中途逃跑更加胆小 "
He's scared to death He's scared to look At his fuckin'yearbook
"他快要被吓死, 他连看都不敢看,在这个他妈的比赛上
Fuck Cranbrook  [ Music Stops ]
" 操他的 Cranbrook "
Fuck a beat! I go a cappella!
操他的节奏. 我有自己的想法.
Fuck a Papa Doc! Fuck a clock! Fuck a trailer! Fuck everybody!
操他的 Papa Doc.操他的 时间. 操他的拖车. 操你们每个人.
Fucky'all if you doubt me!  I'm a piece offuckin' white  trash, I say it proudly!
操这些不相信我的人! 我就是骄傲的说 我是他妈的一堆白色垃圾.
And fuck this battle! I don't want to win! I'm outtie!
操这场比赛. 我才不想他妈的赢.
Here, tell these people something they don't know about me!
好了, 告诉大家一些他们不知道的我的事情吧.
Papa Doc! Whatyou gonna do?!
Papa Doc! 你要怎么做?
D.J.! D.J.! A minute anda half! Spin that shit!
DJ...! DJ...! 一分半钟. 放音乐!
[ All Chanting ] What?! What?! What?!
凭什么?凭什么?
Whoa! Oh! Oh! Oh!
哦,哦
We got a new champion! We got a new champion! B-Rabbit!
我们的新冠军产生了.! 我们的新冠军产生了! B-Rabbit.!
- B-Rabbit! - Let's rol l!
- B-Rabbit.! - 我们走吧.
Fuck Free World! 3-1 -3!
操他的 Free World! 3-1 -3!
[ All Chanting ] B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit--
B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit, B-Rabbit...
Three-One-Third! We in the house!
3-1-3!
Never get it twisted, this is my man right here!
这位才是我的好兄弟!
B-Rabbit! This is my man, right here!
B-Rabbit! 这位是我的好兄弟,
Yo, we have it, Rabbit! Yo, we on ourway, dawg!
我们成功了, Rabbit. 我们上路了
We gonna get that big deal soon!
我们很快就会得到合约的!
And then we go get all the bitches!
到时候我们就去操完所有的婊子!
All the bitches! All the bitches!
所有的婊子!
- Where we goin'?! - I'm goin' back to work!
- 我们要去哪里? - 我要回去工作
Work?!
你去工作?
Get the fuck outta here! You ain't goin' to work!
你他妈的少来了, 你不用去工作了!
Yeah, you the man now, dawg! You ain't gotta work!
你已经蠃了，你不必再去工作了.
Yeah, fuckWink! FuckTha Free World, we are the shit!
是啊,操他的 Wink. 操他的 Free World, 我们才是最好的!
- Hey, what's up, y'all?! - Hold on!
- 你们是怎么了? - 稍等一下.
Look, man, I been thinkin'!
我在想....
You and me to host the battles together!
你和我将一起主持battle.
You know what I'm sayin'?! [ Sighs ]
你知道我在说什么?
Nah! That's you, dawg!
不. 那是你的活.
[ Laughs ] Come on!
少来了.
Tell meyou don't want to host with me!
别说你不想跟我一起了.
I mean, you have everybody lookin' up toyou,
现在每个人都崇拜你
everybody know whoyou are--
每个人都知道你是谁...
[ Sighs ] Yeah, but!!!
是啊,不过...
I think I kinda need to just do my own thing, man!
不过我想做自己的事情,老兄
You know?!
你知道吗?
[ Chuckles ] Yeah! I think I do!
我明白.
A'ight, Rabbit! Peace out, Rabbit!
好的, Rabbit. 好走, Rabbit!
Look.
[Eminem] Look.
If you had, one shot
"If you had one shot
Or one opportunity
" Or one opportunity
To seize everything  you ever wanted
" To seize everything you ever wanted
In one moment
"In one moment
Would you capture it Or just let it slip
" Would you capture it Orjust let it slip
Yo, his palms are sweaty Knees weak, arms are heavy
" Yo, his palms are sweaty Knees weak, arms are heavy
There's vomit on his sweater already mom's spaghetti
" There's vomit on his sweater already mom's spaghetti
He's nervous but on the surface he looks calm and ready
"He's nervous but on the surface he looks calm and ready
To drop bombs but he keeps on forgetting what he wrote down
" To drop bombs but he keeps on forgetting what he wrote down
The whole crowd goes so loud He opens his mouth but the words won 't come out
" The whole crowd goes so loud He opens his mouth but the words won't come out
He 's chokin 'how  everybody's jokin 'now  the clock's run out
"He's chokin'how Everybody's jokin'now The clock's run out
Time 's up, over, blaow  Snap back to reality  Oh, there goes gravity
" Time's up, over, blaow Snap back to reality Oh, there goes gravity
Oh, there goes Rabbit, he choked, he 's so mad but he won 't  give up that easy
" Oh, there goes Rabbit, he choked, he's so mad but he won't give up that easy
No, he won 't have it He knows his whole back's to these ropes
"No, he won't have it He knows his whole back's to these ropes
It don 't matter, he 's dope He knows that, but he 's broke He 's so sad that he knows
"It don't matter, he's dope He knows that, but he's broke He's so sad that he knows
When he goes back to this mobile home, that's when it's back to the lab again
" When he goes back to this mobile home, that's when it's back to the lab again
Yo, this whole rap shit He better go capture this moment
" Yo, this whole rap shit He better go capture this moment
And hope it don 't pass him
"And hope it don't pass him
Just melt in the music The moment you want it you better never let it go
"Just melt in the music The moment you want it you better never let it go
You only get one shot. Do not miss your chance to blow
" You only get one shot Do not miss your chance to blow
This opportunity comes once in a lifetime
" This opportunity comes once in a lifetime
Give it up  Just melt in the music  the moment you want it
" Give it up Just melt in the music the moment you want it
You better never let it go, you only get one shot, do not miss your chance to blow
" You better never let it go You only get one shot, do not miss your chance to blow
This opportunity comes Once in a lifetime. Give it up
" This opportunity comes Once in a lifetime Give it up
Soul's escaping, through  this hole that is gaping
"Soul's escaping, through this hole that is gaping
This world is mine for the taking. Make me king
" This world is mine for the taking Make me king
As we move toward a  new world order A normal life is boring
"As we move toward a New World Order A normal life is boring
But superstardom 's close to postmortem  It only grows harder
"But superstardom's close to postmortem It only grows harder
Homie grows hotter He blows us all over
"Homie grows hotter He blows us all over
His ho 's is all on him  Coast-to-coast shows, he 's known as the Globetrotter
"His ho's is all on him Coast-to-coast shows, he's known as the Globetrotter
Lonely roads, God only knows He 's grown farther from home
"Lonely roads, God only knows He's grown farther from home
He 's no father, he goes  home and barely knows  his own daughter
"He's no father, he goes home and barely knows his own daughter
But hold ya nose cause here goes the cold water
"But hold your nose 'cause here goes the cold water
This hoes don 't want him no mo ', he 's cold prada
"His ho's don't want him no mo, he's cold product
They moved on to the next schmo who flows
"And they moved on to the next schmo who flows
who nose-dove and sold nada And so the soap proper
"He nose-dove and sold nada And so the soap opera
His toll, it unfolds I suppose it's old, partner
"Is told, it unfolds I suppose it's old, partner
But the beat goes on  Dah-da-doe, dug -doe, dah dah dah dah
"But the beat goes on Dah-da-dum, da-dum da-dah
You better lose yourself in the music. The moment you own it You better never let it go
"Lose yourself in the music The moment you want it You better never let it go
Oh,you only get one shot. Do not miss your chance to blow
" You only get one shot Do not miss your chance to blow
cuz opportunity comes once in a lifetime
" This opportunity comes once in a lifetime
Yo, you better lose yourself in the music The moment you own it You better never let it go,
"Lose yourself in the music The moment you want it You better never let it go
You only get one shot. Do not miss your chance to blow
" You only get one shot Do not miss your chance to blow
This opportunity comes once in a lifetime
" This opportunity comes once in a lifetime
Give it up  No more games I'm gonna change
" Give it up "No more games I'm gonna change
What you call rage. Tear this motherfuckin 'roofoff
" What you call rage Tear this motherfuckin'roof off
Like two dogs caged. I was playin ' in the beginning
"Like two dogs caged I was playin'in the beginning
The mood all changed. I been chewed up and spit out and booed offstage
" The mood all changed I been chewed up and spit out and booed off stage
But I kept rhymin' and stepped right in the next cypher
"But I kept rhymin' and stepped right in the next cypher
Best believe somebody's payin ' the pied piper
"Best believe somebody's payin'the pied piper
All the pain inside amplified by the
"All the pain inside amplifiied by the
Fact that I can 't get by with my nine-to-
"Fact that I can't get by with my nine-to-
Five and I can 't provide the right type of@
"Five and I can't provide the right type of
Life for my family 'Cause man, these goddamn food stamps @
"Life for my family 'Cause man, these goddamn food stamps
Don 't buy diapers .And it's no movie There 's no Mekhi Phifer @
"Don't buy diapers And it's no movie There's no Mekhi Phifer
This is my life  and these times are so hard@
" This is my life and these times are so hard
And it's gettin ' even harder Tryin ' to feed and water my seed plus @
"And it's gettin'even harder Tryin'to feed and water my seed plus
Teeter-totter caught up between bein'a father and a prima donna @
" Teeter-totter caught up between bein'a father and a prima donna
Baby momma drama screamin' on her too much for me to wanna stay in one spot @
"Baby momma drama screamin' on her too much for me to wanna stay in one spot
Another day ofmonotony's   gotten me to the point  I'm like a snail @
"Another day of monotony's gotten me to the point I'm like a snail
I've got to formulate a plot or end up in jail or shot
"I've got to formulate a plot or end up in jail or shot
Success is my only motherfuckin'option Failure's not
"Success is my only motherfuckin'option Failure's not
Mom, I love you but  this trailer's got to go
"Mom, I love you but this trailer's got to go
I cannot grow old in Salem's Lot, so here I go It's my shot
"I cannot grow old in Salem's Lot, so here I go It's my shot
Feet fail me not.  This may be the only opportunity that I got
"Feet fail me not This may be the only opportunity that I got
You better Lose yourselfin the music The moment you want it
" You better Lose yourself in the music The moment you want it
You better never let it go.  You only get one shot
" You better never let it go You only get one shot
Do not miss your chance to blow  this opportunity comes once in a lifetime
"Do not miss your chance to blow this opportunity comes once in a lifetime
Give it up Lose yourselfin the music. The moment you want it
" Give it up Lose yourself in the music The moment you want it
You better never let it go  .You only get one shot
" You better never let it go You only get one shot
Do not miss your chance to blow  this opportunity  comes once in a lifetime
"Do not miss your chance to blow this opportunity comes once in a lifetime
Move it up
"Move it up
You can do anything,  you set your mind to, man.
You can do anything you set your mind to, man.
[ Fades ]
"[Fades]